<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Code and Unload by Codio</title>
  <subtitle>While we code we often have lots of ideas brewing around. Ideas we'd like to unload onto you</subtitle>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Securing Project Previews</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/secure-previewing/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/secure-previewing/</id>
    <published>2013-04-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are always extremely mindful of ensuring that your Codio experience is as secure and safe as possible. So with this in mind, we just rolled out a change in the way that you preview private projects. Previously, we used a cookie to authenticate such...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are always extremely mindful of ensuring that your Codio experience is as secure and safe as possible. So with this in mind, we just rolled out a change in the way that you preview private projects. Previously, we used a cookie to authenticate such requests. This was done to ensure that only those with read permissions could actually preview. However, this method is prone to abuse and could allow an attacker to preview your private projects, regardless of whether they had permission to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mornings release completely removes this dependence on cookies to authenticate when previewing. Instead, you will be prompted to enter your Codio login if and when you preview a private project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note, that you will not be prompted to authenticate when previewing public projects - for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coding + Math + Art + Physics = FUN</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/coding-art-math/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/coding-art-math/</id>
    <published>2013-04-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you may have read in previous posts, we're trying to change the approach to IT education and we believe that coding needs to be centre stage - well at least on stage - in schools. One of the great things about coding is that it can be fun and can...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you may have read in previous posts, we&amp;#39;re trying to change the approach to IT education and we believe that coding needs to be centre stage - well at least on stage - in schools. One of the great things about coding is that it can be fun and can draw on other strengths and talents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example projects you see below draw on creativity, math, physics and even a smattering of art. We are trying to get people to realize that &lt;strong&gt;CODING IS FUN&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone has cool examples of code that draws on talent and creativity from other areas, please add your suggestions in the comments below this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Explore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are three simple projects displayed in the Codio IDE (which is live and clickable, so go ahead). Each of these can be run in the browser (press Preview button) and you can explore the code in the IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Tearable Cloth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT:&lt;/strong&gt; this is a live IDE, not an image, so explore the code and press Preview to run the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://codio.com/codio/Tear-able-Cloth-Demo" width="900" height="500" frameborder="0" marginheight="20" marginwidth="35" scrolling="auto"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Multi-Touch Boids&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT:&lt;/strong&gt; this is a live IDE, not an image, so explore the code and press Preview to run the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://codio.com/codio/Multitouch-Boids-Demo" width="900" height="500" frameborder="0" marginheight="20" marginwidth="35" scrolling="auto"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Animated Text Demo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT:&lt;/strong&gt; this is a live IDE, not an image, so explore the code and press Preview to run the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://codio.com/codio/Animated-Text-Fill-Demo" width="900" height="500" frameborder="0" marginheight="20" marginwidth="35" scrolling="auto"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>No teachers, no problem - an inspirational TED Talk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/sugata-mitra/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/sugata-mitra/</id>
    <published>2013-04-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This TED talk by Sugata Mitra is truly inspirational. It's shows that kids in the digital age can learn incredibly well without any formal teaching when they form communities and use their natural resourcefulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/sugata_mitra_build_a_school_in_the_cloud.html" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are four of my favorite parts...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This TED talk by Sugata Mitra is truly inspirational. It&amp;#39;s shows that kids in the digital age can learn incredibly well without any formal teaching when they form communities and use their natural resourcefulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/sugata_mitra_build_a_school_in_the_cloud.html" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are four of my favorite parts if you don&amp;#39;t have time to watch the whole video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;The hole-in-the-wall computer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sugata tells the story of how he put a &amp;#39;hole-in-the-wall&amp;#39; computer, connected to the web, in a small village in India where the kids had never seen a computer and couldn&amp;#39;t speak any English. He then went away for 3 months and left them to it. When he came back, the kids had not only collectively figured out how to use the computer, surf the web etc. but they had taught themselves English so they could figure out how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Teaching DNA replication to 12 year olds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He deposited a hole-in-the-wall computer in another village and then asked kids to find out all they could about DNA Replication, certain that they would fail at this complex task. They didn&amp;#39;t become biochemists but they achieved a 50% score in a test for people 8 years older at a private school in New Delhi with a proper biochemistry teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;The English Accent experiment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An experiment to teach Indian kids to speak English without their usual very strong accents (and therefore improve their job prospects). The solution involved not a second of teaching. He gave them a speech-to-text recognition engine and left them to it. If there accents were not good enough, the computer could not recognize their speech and nothing would come up on screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that there are some important lessons to be learnt from these stories. Kids will learn if they are given some very basic opportunities. If teachers are not available, well never mind. If you add great, modern teachers into the mix, who are capable of teaching not just their class of 30, but a class of 300,000 - now that&amp;#39;s teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Post-Curriculum approach to teaching programming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/post-curriculum/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/post-curriculum/</id>
    <published>2013-04-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Does the West realize just how important programming is?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries like India, Russia, China, Vietnam, Romania certainly do! These countries are producing ever more, better quality developers every day. Small wonder as programming is extremely well...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Does the West realize just how important programming is?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries like India, Russia, China, Vietnam, Romania certainly do! These countries are producing ever more, better quality developers every day. Small wonder as programming is extremely well paid, creative, fun and the developer stereotype is now &amp;#39;geek chic&amp;#39; rather than &amp;#39;spotty nerd&amp;#39;. So, what&amp;#39;s going wrong in the West?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the US, the global leader in tech, less than 2.4% of college students graduate with a degree in computer science - &lt;strong&gt;fewer than 10 years ago&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the UK&amp;#39;s Cambridge University, today&amp;#39;s Computer Science students interview with some web design skills but little knowldge of coding, whereas 10 years ago students were often hobbyist programmers. This problem gave rise to the massively popular Raspberry Pi. (&lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/about"&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; makes for interesting reading).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.code.org"&gt;Code.org&lt;/a&gt; was launched in the US to try to address the severe developing problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the infographic below for some sobering stats from Code.org (sorry about mangling the infographic, &lt;a href="http://www.code.org/stats"&gt;here is the original&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Code.org stats" src="/s/img/blog/codeinfographic2-21-1-e9dc9307.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;The Problem in Schools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most school curricula focus on using Word, Excel and office productivity tools - things that kids these days pick up in 5 minutes without any instruction. Governments are now trying to put in place curricula that incorporate coding. It&amp;#39;s quite easy to imagine how a committee designed curriculum might look. Not compatible with the dynamic world of IT and especially not when it comes to learning to code. By the time a curriculum has been worked through and published, large chunks will be out of date and it will be static for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;The Solution : CrowdTeaching &amp;amp; Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case educators don&amp;#39;t think it can be done, I suggest they take a look at the open source community. It is populated by very smart, community oriented people who know how to code and many of whom are all too happy to try to explain how things work. Take a look at GitHub, which alone has nearly 4 million developers working collaboratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source software is at or near the centre of every single great IT company without exception. Ask Google, Twitter, Facebook, IBM, Accenture - open source works and is used extensively. Apply the open source approach and ideals to tutorials and teaching people to code, whether beginner, intermediate or advanced, and you have a recipe for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can take any tutorial made by anyone and then &amp;#39;fork&amp;#39; (copy) it and make improvements. These improvements can be small, in which case they are requested to be re-absorbed by the original creator, or they can be the starting point for an entirely new direction. There are no absolute &amp;#39;Owners&amp;#39; as every project is permissively open sourced and can be found and updated by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;How Codio will enable CrowdTeaching &amp;amp; Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio it about to announce several features that will enable this to happen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a teaching platform and feature set based on the Codio IDE (all completely free) called &lt;a href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/say-it-with-a-sample/"&gt;Codio:Annotations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a GitHub based content framework for content creation and collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a standard educational license that all content should use, allowing completely unrestricted copying and modifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an active curation program backed by a Codio staff that will provide guidance and organization for any programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a curation feature set within Codio that allows people to categorize, tag and vote, helping learners find the best material quickly and easily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these features, there will be a vehicle for a truly post-curriculum approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;Developers don&amp;#39;t have to use Codio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Codio will have a unique and rich set of code annotation and documentation features, we don&amp;#39;t want to force people to use Codio. The Codio:Annotation features can be accessed from a developer&amp;#39;s favorite IDE, but there is no requirement to use Codio to submit content to the GitHub library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;What about Teachers and Teaching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim for these initiatives to be a rich resource for teachers to draw on. As every bit of content is open and collaborative, we expect forward looking teachers to be active participants and take inspiration from others and pass this on. They can structure their own courses around existing materials, always looking to update and use the best content available. We think this will attract the new generation of teachers as well as the new generation of coders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Turning students on to coding - celebrity coders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to organize global Webinars and interviews with luminaries from the world of coding. These webinars will stimulate pupils and students to hear straight from the mouths of important software developers why it is such a great profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_7"&gt;Teach to 30,000 not 30&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is also a fantastic way of bringing the best out of teachers. Imagine a teacher who is doing a stupendous job of motivating their students. Isn’t it a real waste for them to have their brilliance shine only on their own class of students? Their content is available to the whole world and they can even arrange a course or webinar that is broadcast globally. Less collaboratively inclined teachers can still piggy back on those materials and use them with their students in whatever way works best for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_8"&gt;So, let&amp;#39;s act&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that this mini manifesto is the foundation for a revolutionary approach to the way coding is taught and gives access to a truly exciting and lucrative career to huge numbers of students. It is a great thing that developing countries can expand their economies thanks to IT and I don&amp;#39;t know of anyone who begrudges them this one bit. However, it is shameful that complacent western countries stand idly by and watch as IT skills drain away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Add a Readme file to your project</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/add-a-readme-file-to-your-project/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/add-a-readme-file-to-your-project/</id>
    <published>2013-04-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/04/drag-and-drop-in-the-file-explorer"&gt;dragging and dropping files in the file explorer&lt;/a&gt;, we've just added another new feature that will really help others find out all they need to know about your projects. Just add a readme file into your project, and it will be shown...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/04/drag-and-drop-in-the-file-explorer"&gt;dragging and dropping files in the file explorer&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;#39;ve just added another new feature that will really help others find out all they need to know about your projects. Just add a readme file into your project, and it will be shown by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Readme File in your projects" src="/s/img/blog/readme-84ba748a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as you create a file called &lt;code&gt;readme&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;readme.txt&lt;/code&gt;, it will be shown in the first tab of the IDE when your project is opened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want to make your readme look good, use the excellent &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; syntax to give your &lt;a href="https://codio.com/joelmoss/Log/tree/Log/README.md"&gt;readme&lt;/a&gt; some &lt;a href="https://codio.com/joelmoss/Log"&gt;style&lt;/a&gt;. Just use the &lt;code&gt;md&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;markdown&lt;/code&gt; file extension.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codio:Annotations - Say it with a sample</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/say-it-with-a-sample/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/say-it-with-a-sample/</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we were building the Codio IDE, we suddenly realized that we have in our hands a unique platform that helps people explain code - any programming language, any skill level, not just beginners. It is ideal for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Development tutorials (any skill...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we were building the Codio IDE, we suddenly realized that we have in our hands a unique platform that helps people explain code - any programming language, any skill level, not just beginners. It is ideal for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development tutorials (any skill level)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API samples and explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer documentation samples and tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documenting and explaining advanced frameworks, libraries etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example code projects of any sort and any level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Tell us what you think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will offer this as a completely free platform, but it will require real effort a) to add the annotation features and b) to provide the infrastructure. It is really important to us to know that people are behind our efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you like what you see, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio is an awesome platform for code examples and tutorials, any language, any skill level" target="_blank"&gt;Tweet about us&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/CodioHQ" target="_blank"&gt;like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or just leave a comment at the bottom of this page. The more support we get for this, the more we&amp;#39;ll throw at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Getting behind Education&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our real hopes is that Codio provides a new way for schools, universities and other programming courses to teach, based on real working code, and in a way that does not require the learner to assemble a full development stack before being able to start tinkering. By offering these features and a real web IDE for free, we hope to clear away a few obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Video Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post describes things step by step, but if you prefer a video run-through, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/ypR9CUG1Tjo?autoplay=1&amp;hd=1&amp;fs=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;rel=0&amp;"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;What&amp;#39;s missing from most tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know what most tutorials look like. It doesn&amp;#39;t matter if it is a tutorial for a complete newbie or something that is explaining a complex framework, API or library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is an example of a high quality tutorial from webplatform.org, which you can scroll through or you can &lt;a href="http://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/tutorials/creating_and_modifying_html" target="_blank"&gt;open the full page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style="width:700px; height:400px" src="http://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/tutorials/creating_and_modifying_html"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very well written indeed, but there is a lot to digest here, and this is usually the case with web and video tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am learning about a something new, there are two things I always yearn for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tutorial seamlessly wrapped up with a &lt;strong&gt;real, fully working code example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactivity - being able to run, explore, fork, edit etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... and this is exactly what Codio:Annotations offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;The same tutorial run in Codio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;#39;s see how Codio can change the approach to the same tutorial&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;Better - Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can load any development project already today. Just include a link (&lt;a href="https://codio.com/fmay/HTML-Create-and-Modify/tree/App/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;try clicking here&lt;/a&gt;) from within your page or use a Codio widget to go to the project. Try it out and see what it feels like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codio.com/fmay/HTML-Create-and-Modify/tree/App/index.html"&gt;&lt;img alt="Drag and Drop in the File Explorer" src="/s/img/blog/codio-widget-013e7427.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Better - Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are lots of situations where I want to make things even more seamless and avoid having to leave the tutorial page. You can embed the Codio IDE straight into your web page as shown below. It&amp;#39;s a simple project, but have a quick explore ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style="width:800px; height:600px" src="https://codio.com/fmay/HTML-Create-and-Modify/tree/App/index.html"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Codio IDE, your sample can be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewed and explored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forked and edited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run (if it is an HTML5+CSS+JS project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_7"&gt;Better - Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following steps have not been built yet, but will be with your support. The screenshots below are mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine being able to explore the code freely by clicking on the icons within the IDE wherever you see one. I will explain further down how this can all be set up in your source project using your regular IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-settabfromlink-f517eaea.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see rich text (as shown), images, audio or video depending on the icon you click on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_8"&gt;Better - Step 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to, I can put the entire tutorial itself into the project and then get a guided tour through the code, either by click on the navigation buttons ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-guided-d9684114.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... or by scrolling through the embedded tutorial, which syncs automatically with the associated piece of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-scroll-1-b2090dc3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_9"&gt;Better - Step 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final piece in the jigsaw is also really important - how to find great tutorials. We will build a curated area where each tutorial can be posted. Anyone who has built one can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post it to a language area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And within that, a subject matter area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users to vote on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage users to post comments to other learners and to the author so it can be improved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will look something like this ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-curation-6556e3c0.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_10"&gt;How does a developer build a Codio tutorial?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make this as easy and unobtrusive as possible. Here are the key points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should work for any programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should be able create the content from absolutely any IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should not mess up your source code or interfere with the way you would want to write code naturally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should be able to import effortlessly from a ZIP file, Git or Mercurial repo so that future modifications and updates are a no-brainer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshot below shows how tokens are added into the source file ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/ks-tokens-88d68eee.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this one shows how you construct the annotations file. This provides both guided tours, scrolling as well as the project structure annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/ks-annotation-file-aa29cc9b.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="support"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_11"&gt;Please support us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you agree that Codio is a force for good whether in education or for professional development, then doing any of the following will really help us know we are pointed in the right direction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio is an awesome platform for code examples and tutorials, any language, any skill level" target="_blank"&gt;Tweet your support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/CodioHQ" target="_blank"&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a comment at the bottom of this page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just let others know about Codio:Annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Codio Team&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
