<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codio Blog</title>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Server Side Development in Codio</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/server-side-development/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/server-side-development/</id>
    <published>2014-01-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is the best web based IDE for client-side development. However, when it comes to server-side development, things start to get a little tricky. We currently provide no server-side environment where you can run your server code. Over the last few...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is the best web based IDE for client-side development. However, when it comes to server-side development, things start to get a little tricky. We currently provide no server-side environment where you can run your server code. Over the last few months we&amp;#39;ve been working hard to solve this problem, and this week we started opening up Codio Boxes to a select few beta testers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be adding more beta users over the next few weeks. If you want in, drop &lt;a href="mailto:ijobling@codio.com"&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt; an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution has been far from easy, and has made an already complex infrastructure that little bit more complex. But we spent a lot of time thinking and planning the best solution we could possibly provide you. In this post, I want to briefly explain what the new Codio Boxes are and what benefits they will give you when they launch in February 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;New and Shiny&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the following new shiny stuff that will be available to you very soon...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_1"&gt;Docker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of every Codio project is the amazing &lt;a href="https://www.docker.io"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. We wanted every single project to have its own isolated server environment, with terminal access and the ability to do as much as you want without restriction. Docker lets us do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create or open up a project, we spin up a Docker container at the same time. Open up the Codio Terminal and you now have a full-stack server-side development environment in the cloud. We provide a load of languages pre-installed for you, including NodeJS (via &lt;a href="https://github.com/creationix/nvm"&gt;NVM&lt;/a&gt;) and Ruby (via &lt;a href="https://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv"&gt;rbenv&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_2"&gt;Box Parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Box Parts is a simple package manager that we provide, and gives you command line access to quickly install the most popular packages, including MongoDB, Java, PHP, Redis and MySQL. There will be loads more available with more added over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing any of these packages is extremely fast, as we do all the time-consuming compilation steps for you. All you gotta do is install the binaries that we&amp;#39;ve created for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s as easy as &lt;code&gt;parts install mysql&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Box Parts is built with Ruby and is open source. Head on over to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/boxparts"&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; to check it out. This is the place to request missing packages, or - even better - contribute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_3"&gt;Runtime&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every project will also allow you to access your running processes via a public facing domain name. For example, if you want to run a Ruby on Rails server over port 3000, just install Rails and start the Rails server. Then point your browser to &lt;code&gt;YOURPROJECT.USERNAME.codio.com:3000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will allow the port range &lt;code&gt;1024-4096&lt;/code&gt; for your own services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A future blog post will go into further detail about how we are achieving all this, and what technology we are using.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Paid Subscriptions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/subscriptions/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/subscriptions/</id>
    <published>2014-01-14T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce that with immediate effect, you can now purchase a Codio Subscription! This means that for only &lt;strong&gt;$8 per month&lt;/strong&gt;, you can continue to create and keep a &lt;strong&gt;truly unlimited&lt;/strong&gt; number of private and public projects on Codio...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce that with immediate effect, you can now purchase a Codio Subscription! This means that for only &lt;strong&gt;$8 per month&lt;/strong&gt;, you can continue to create and keep a &lt;strong&gt;truly unlimited&lt;/strong&gt; number of private and public projects on Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has a few implications for existing users and we want to clarify what this means for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Public Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no changes here. If you have only public projects in your account then there is no need to take a paid subscription. You can continue to work with as many public projects as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Existing Private Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already created one or more private projects, then we are providing a grace period of 30 days from now, during which time you can keep these projects private without the need to purchase a subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the 30 day grace period, these projects will be disabled. To access such projects, you have two choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch the project from private to public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep them private and purchase a Subscription for $8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you purchase a subscription, all disabled projects will automatically be re-enabled and will be kept private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;New Private Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have not yet purchased a subscription, but you want to create a new private project or switch a public project private, then you will need to purchase a subscription first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Codio Deployment Targets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer several ways to deploy your apps, and one of those involves that we host your static content. This is called the Codio deployment type. This type is now only available to users with a subscription. All other deployment types are still free no matter if you have a Subscription or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;How to Purchase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two place where you can create a Subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/code&gt; menu item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you switch a public project to private (from the &lt;code&gt;Project &amp;gt; Settings&lt;/code&gt; menu item).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see the following screen where you can enter your credit card details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="subscribe" src="/s/img/blog/subscribe-1-d7351dc7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;Group Subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not currently offer this but it is planned in the near future. This will allow a company to manage centralized payments for a group of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Purchase History &amp;amp; Invoices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be able to find this from the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/code&gt; menu item. You will see the following screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="subscribe" src="/s/img/blog/subscribe-2-f06101a2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_7"&gt;Changing Credit Card Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change your credit card details at any time by going to the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/code&gt; menu item and clicking on the &amp;#39;Card Details&amp;#39; tab.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Happy New Year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/happy-new-year/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/happy-new-year/</id>
    <published>2014-01-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy new year to you all, and we hope you all had a great Christmas. I'm recovering from too much food and drink and pondering what 2014 will bring. As far as Codio is concerned, it's all guns blazing, and we've got &lt;a href="/s/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/"&gt;BIG plans&lt;/a&gt;. We'll be revealing more...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy new year to you all, and we hope you all had a great Christmas. I&amp;#39;m recovering from too much food and drink and pondering what 2014 will bring. As far as Codio is concerned, it&amp;#39;s all guns blazing, and we&amp;#39;ve got &lt;a href="/s/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/"&gt;BIG plans&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;ll be revealing more over the coming weeks and months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for now, we&amp;#39;ve got a few goodies that we quietly shipped over the festive period. So think of these as slightly belated Christmas presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;File Templates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest new feature that shipped just before Christmas, was developed by one of our awesome engineers as part of his Friday Hack Day; a weekly day of anything goes hacking on Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/s/s/docs/ide/ide-general/templates/"&gt;File Templates&lt;/a&gt; allow you to create a new file based on a selection of code templates, such as a PHP class, or Python script, or even a plain HTML page. When you create a new file, you will have the option of populating that new file with a template of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="templates" src="/s/img/blog/templates-3c4aaaf2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already provide several templates out of the box, but if none of those are what you want, you can also edit these or even create your own templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of several new features and improvements that we have already shipped, and that came out of our weekly Hack Day. Here&amp;#39;s to plenty more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Single click directory opening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another improvement that has come out of us listening to what you want...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you now click a directory name in the file tree, that directory will be expanded without requiring a second click. This makes things more consistent with file opening. Simply put, it means that a single click is all you need to open a file or directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, you can still right-click any item to access the context menu, which includes the ability to rename and delete the item.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tab Cycling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/tab-cycling/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/tab-cycling/</id>
    <published>2013-12-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You've been asking and we've been listening. So today we made it easy to quickly switch tabs without having to use your mouse. Just hitting &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+.&lt;/code&gt; will switch your current tab to the next on the right, and &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+,&lt;/code&gt; will switch to tab on the...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ve been asking and we&amp;#39;ve been listening. So today we made it easy to quickly switch tabs without having to use your mouse. Just hitting &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+.&lt;/code&gt; will switch your current tab to the next on the right, and &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+,&lt;/code&gt; will switch to tab on the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, if you don&amp;#39;t like those keybindings, open up your &lt;a href="https://codio.com/p/preferences"&gt;preferences&lt;/a&gt; and change the &lt;code&gt;tab_switch_left&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tab_switch_right&lt;/code&gt; item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tab Switching" src="/s/img/blog/tab-switching-944148bf.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Command Bar</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/command-bar/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/command-bar/</id>
    <published>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're a Sublime Text user, you'll probably use the Command Palette (&lt;code&gt;Cmd-Shift-P&lt;/code&gt;). This is a great way to access all commands from a single keyboard shortcut rather than digging around and trying to find what you want in all the various menu options...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re a Sublime Text user, you&amp;#39;ll probably use the Command Palette (&lt;code&gt;Cmd-Shift-P&lt;/code&gt;). This is a great way to access all commands from a single keyboard shortcut rather than digging around and trying to find what you want in all the various menu options. And if you don&amp;#39;t know the keyboard shortcut for a particular command, it&amp;#39;s a very fast way of discovering it without searching the menu or docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re excited to tell you that Codio now has its very own &lt;a href="/s/docs/command-bar"&gt;Command Bar&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="command bar" src="/s/img/blog/command-bar-e4789305.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Cmd+Shift+P&lt;/code&gt; (Mac) or &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shft+P&lt;/code&gt; (PC/Linux) and the Command Bar will appear. Just type any part of the command you&amp;#39;re looking for and the list will narrow down to match your input. Press &lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt; or click on the command and it will be executed instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as being able to access everything you can find in the menu, you can also toggle a few common preferences, and trigger anything that can be accessed by a keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Git and a Tease of what is to Come!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/</id>
    <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning we rolled out a large and quite a significant change to the underlying infrastructure of Codio. For most of you, you won't notice anything different, but it is worth mentioning to you what we changed, how this may affect you, and why we...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning we rolled out a large and quite a significant change to the underlying infrastructure of Codio. For most of you, you won&amp;#39;t notice anything different, but it is worth mentioning to you what we changed, how this may affect you, and why we did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;A Little Background...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is quite a unique beast from your familiar desktop based IDE, and the reason for that is down to the open and collaborative nature of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desktop IDE is designed to be used in a single-user environment. You open a project and code away without any other users seeing what you are doing, or being able to affect what you are doing. Until you pull or push via source control, you are working in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A browser-based IDE like Codio is almost the complete opposite of the above, especially for public projects. A public project is open and readable by anyone, at any time. You could be coding away while several others are reading your code, and if those other users have write access, they will also be editing code. This is great for open source, as it allows a level of collaboration not previously possible on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this introduces some unique challenges for us, especially in the way Git is used. Git is not designed for a multi-user environment. Committing, branching, merging; these are all actions that you run in isolation, safely away from your collaborators. Only when you push, pull or work with remotes do you start to interact with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We initially built in Git support for Codio based on a system of multiple working copies. This meant that each branch used a separate working copy or set of files, and allowed you to work on any branch without affecting or being affected by others. This worked great, but meant we had to wrap some Git commands to allow them to work with these multiple working copies, and that meant we couldn&amp;#39;t provide full Git support without considerable work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;So what changed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came to a realization that we probably over-thought this issue a little, and perhaps even created problems that were not real-word problems in the first place. We listened to you telling us you wanted access to all your favourite Git commands and options. So this morning we removed multiple working copies, and changed all projects to use Git in the way it was designed to be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;How does this affect me?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, probably very little. But it is important to know one simple thing... that now all Git commands will affect all users equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when you checkout a different branch, others on that project will also be switched to use that branch. Which is actually what you would expect to happen anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing here, is that Git now works in a way that you are familiar with, and will allow us to provide full Git support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Why have you done this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me on to the juicy part of this post, and the tease...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is awesome when working on front-end development, but we recognise that when it comes to server-side development, there are a few hoops you have to jump through. We always knew that this would be the case, and that we would need to build out a solution for working on server-side dev. So now that time has come, and this Git change is the first step toward the goal of full-stack development using Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early next year, you will be able to use Codio to build almost any kind of project, from the simplest static site, to the complex; and using almost any language you wish, including NodeJS, PHP, Python and Ruby. Every single Codio project will have its own full-stack development environment in the cloud, meaning that all you need is your browser and Codio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once that is in place, the entire Git tool-set will be available without ever having to leave Codio. You will be able to use Git the way you want, and without any restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
