<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codio Blog</title>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>I Love Open Source</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/10/ilos/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/10/ilos/</id>
    <published>2013-10-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want to briefly talk about an interesting metamorphosis - better know as gross scope creep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to give some sort of acknowledgment and support for the many open source projects we use. What started off as a single web page on the Codio site...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want to briefly talk about an interesting metamorphosis - better know as gross scope creep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to give some sort of acknowledgment and support for the many open source projects we use. What started off as a single web page on the Codio site turned into a few weeks of full-on application development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is &amp;quot;I Love Open Source&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://iloveopensource.io"&gt;&lt;img alt="header" src="/s/img/blog/ilos-blog-hdr-69201222.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/75609049?autoplay=1&amp;hd=1" target="_blank"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for a really quick overview of I Love Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;What is &amp;quot;I Love Open Source&amp;quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://iloveopensource.io"&gt;http://iloveopensource.io&lt;/a&gt; is a full fledged application (it is itself Open Source and forkable on GitHub) that encourages any GitHub user or organization to publicly state which Open Source projects they use. And in the process of doing so, they have the opportunity to donate something, if they wish, to any of those projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Codio Loves Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you click the logo below, you&amp;#39;ll see our support page and which repos we use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.iloveopensource.io/orgs/523c6c7f861be70200000007"&gt;&lt;img alt="ilos" src="../img/ilos-logo-lightbg-78b1be7c.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Supporters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an example Supporter page with 3 OS projects it&amp;#39;s acknowledging. You can see the person contributes code and cash to the jquery project. You can also see the donate options beneath the GitHub Octocat logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are encouraged to link to your supporter page from your website or README.md file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ilos" src="/s/img/blog/ilos-sup-page-0af95014.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;Maintainers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone owning a repo that wants support, whether simple acknowledgments or cash, heads over to the Maintainers section and sets up their donation preferences (Gittip, Flattr, Paypal, Wire etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when people are setting up their support or when anyone sees a support page, they are always gently given the opportunity to donate there and then. See the above image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;What about Gittip, Flattr &amp;amp; Paypal etc?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Love Open Source does not handle any payments at all. We allow the developer to use their own existing Gittip, Flattr and Paypal buttons. For the record, we do not take any commissions or have any commercial involvement with any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that I Love Open Source is itself Open Source and does not handle any cash transactions means that it can concentrate on acknowledgment in general and providing an easy way to support and donate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Code and Idea Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Love Open Source can be &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/iloveopensource"&gt;forked on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; so feel free to fix code or add features and issue a pull request. Before you embark on huge endeavours, it may make sense to &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/iloveopensource/issues?state=open"&gt;raise an Issue&lt;/a&gt; first here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any great ideas you want to discuss or bugs you want to report should be done &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/iloveopensource/issues?state=open"&gt;here in GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt; also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_7"&gt;Many thanks to Digital Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short but important word of thanks goes to &lt;a href="http://www.digitalocean.com"&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;. They have been very generous in providing I Love Open Source with their lovely servers at no cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_8"&gt;Please Support Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only support we ask for is that you Tweet about this project so the word spreads fast. We&amp;#39;re @iloshq on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better, &lt;a href="http://iloveopensource.io"&gt;create your own I Love Open Source Supporter page right now&lt;/a&gt; and link to it from your web site or README.md file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rsync Deployment, Tab Context Menu &amp;amp; CSS Auto-Completion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/10/rsync-deployment-tab-context-menu-css-auto-completion/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/10/rsync-deployment-tab-context-menu-css-auto-completion/</id>
    <published>2013-10-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Rsync Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, we added yet another option to our deployment feature, but one that we think will really make a difference when developing in Codio. You can now deploy to almost any server via Rsync, which makes it even faster...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Rsync Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, we added yet another option to our deployment feature, but one that we think will really make a difference when developing in Codio. You can now deploy to almost any server via Rsync, which makes it even faster to get your code from Codio and onto your development environment, or even into production. And because it is Rsync, it will selectively deploy &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; your changes, making it even faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make it easier and faster to write and deploy your code, and we&amp;#39;re still working to take that even further, but for now you can write code, and get it onto your development environment extremely quickly via the new Rsync deployment option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Tab Context Menu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tab Context Menu" src="/s/img/blog/tab-context-menu-0437cea7.png" /&gt; You can now right click any tab and get a new context menu. This menu will allow you to quickly do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close the current file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close all other files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close all files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close files to the right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close files to the left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, these have keyboard shortcuts which you can customise via your &lt;a href="https://codio.com/s/docs/settings-prefs/codio-prefs/"&gt;user preferences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSS Auto Completion" src="/s/img/blog/css-auto-complete-c454d3b0.png" /&gt; CSS Auto-Completion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, we just shipped support for auto-completion in CSS code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start typing any CSS rule name and hit your auto-complete keyboard shortcut (&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Space&lt;/code&gt;), and you&amp;#39;ll be shown a list of all matching CSS rules. Scroll through the list for the one you want, hit &lt;code&gt;tab&lt;/code&gt;, and it will be auto-completed for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
  img[alt="Tab Context Menu"],
  img[alt="CSS Auto Completion"] {
    float:left;
    margin-right:50px;
    margin-bottom:20px;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Latest and Greatest - Why we only Support Modern Browsers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/latest-and-greatest-why-we-only-support-modern-browsers/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/latest-and-greatest-why-we-only-support-modern-browsers/</id>
    <published>2013-09-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So we've been getting a few questions about our browser support recently, in particular why it is that we only support the most recent versions of the most popular browsers. So I thought I'd answer that question here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, it all boils down...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;#39;ve been getting a few questions about our browser support recently, in particular why it is that we only support the most recent versions of the most popular browsers. So I thought I&amp;#39;d answer that question here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, it all boils down to two things...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Maintainability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is an extremely complex beast, built up of several individual applications and all needing to live together in perfect harmony. So needless to say, it takes a fair bit of work to maintain, and ensure that everything keeps working as it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as you will most likely know, building a web application is an entirely different experience than building server side applications. Most of the time, this experience is great, but the one big thing that sets web development apart is the endless struggle to make your app look and work great in dozens and dozens of browser and OS combinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to test each browser on every popular operating system, and we have to do this continually. Of course, there are tools and services out there that can help us with this, but it is still very hard and extremely resource intensive. Because of our &amp;quot;Ship It&amp;quot; mantra, we need to move and react fast, and this includes browser testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is an environment designed and built to make your life easier. It includes some pretty unique features, as well as a lot of features that you all expect to see in the the best IDEs and text editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old browsers can severely restrict and constrain what we are able to build. For example, our support for multi-panel layouts wouldn&amp;#39;t be possible without the latest FlexBox features of CSS3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We simply wouldn&amp;#39;t be able to deliver the best features and the best user experience to you, if we still had to support old browsers. We would only be shipping new features, improvements and bug fixes every couple of weeks, instead of every day, like we do currently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that you deserve the latest and greatest, so we only support the latest and greatest browsers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome 21 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox 22 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IE 10 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safari 6 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opera 12 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Better Looking Annotations &amp;amp; Full Screen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/better-looking-annotations-and-full-screen/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/better-looking-annotations-and-full-screen/</id>
    <published>2013-09-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we shipped some big improvements to the way you view and navigate through Annotations, and also added a handy way to open any tab in full screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annotations are a great way to create interactive, code-based tutorials and tours...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we shipped some big improvements to the way you view and navigate through Annotations, and also added a handy way to open any tab in full screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annotations are a great way to create interactive, code-based tutorials and tours. Just create a project and annotate your code using simple comments-based tags. Then viewers of your project will then be able to take a tour of your code, or click around on the annotations that you have created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;#39;s release makes Annotations Tour content much less obtrusive. By moving the content out of a dialog window and into a tab - like everything else in Codio - you no longer have to move or resize the dialog out of the way. The code and Annotations content are now shown side-by-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/s/docs/annotations"&gt;Read the docs&lt;/a&gt; for more on Annotations and how to create and use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Full Screen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve also sneaked in a nice new item to your &lt;code&gt;View&lt;/code&gt; menu. Just click &lt;code&gt;Full Screen&lt;/code&gt; and your current tab will be expanded into full screen. Or better still, just hit &lt;code&gt;F11&lt;/code&gt; on your keyboard for a quick shortcut. And if you don&amp;#39;t like &lt;code&gt;F11&lt;/code&gt;, open up your Preferences from the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; User&lt;/code&gt; menu item, and simply override the &lt;code&gt;fullscreen&lt;/code&gt; option. I set mine to &lt;code&gt;Cmd-Shift-F&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ide]
fullscreen = Cmd-Shift-F
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;And one more thing..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;#39;ve improved the File Tree, by adding arrows to let you expand/collapse directories. Simple change, but it now lets you more easily see what is expanded and what isn&amp;#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improving Performance - Tab Switching</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/improving-performance-tab-switching/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/improving-performance-tab-switching/</id>
    <published>2013-09-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Friedel Ziegelmayer</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you might know we have switched our editor from &lt;a href="http://ace.c9.io"&gt;Ace&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://codemirror.net"&gt;CodeMirror&lt;/a&gt;. The optimisations that we already had in place are now obsolete. So I've started looking at optimising the way we use &lt;a href="http://codemirror.net"&gt;CodeMirror&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Where to optimise?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my adventure by importing...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you might know we have switched our editor from &lt;a href="http://ace.c9.io"&gt;Ace&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://codemirror.net"&gt;CodeMirror&lt;/a&gt;. The optimisations that we already had in place are now obsolete. So I&amp;#39;ve started looking at optimising the way we use &lt;a href="http://codemirror.net"&gt;CodeMirror&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Where to optimise?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my adventure by importing the complete &lt;a href="http://nodejs.org"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; repository into Codio and simply opening, reading and editing different files. I immediately noticed that when I opened multiple large files and switched between those, it would take a fair bit of time. So there I had found my first place to optimise... tab switching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Measure it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened up the dev tools and started profiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/flames-javascript-cpu-profile-running-e0c5401e.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I looked at the time it took for switching tabs, I saw that it took a total time of about two seconds to simply switch between two tabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/flames-graph-before-0b9cfa42.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image above shows the flame chart I recorded for switching. The two seconds can be seen if you look at the vertical axis, while the horizontal axis shows the call stack at a given moment. For more information on flame charts see this &lt;a href="http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/developertools/revolutions2013/#toc-flame-chart"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.html5rocks.com"&gt;html5rocks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Find the biggest time thief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at these call stacks I found that the most time-consuming method was &lt;code&gt;CodeMirror.refresh()&lt;/code&gt;, which repaints the whole display area of the instance to update all information. But what was more concerning was that a single call was taking so long. I realised that this method was called not only once, but three times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Optimizations: 1st Round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my new knowledge I went into the code tracing the stack calls and then eliminating two of the three calls to &lt;code&gt;CodeMirror.refresh&lt;/code&gt; when switching from one tab to another. My work did not go unrewarded, I ended up with this new graph resulting in an overall switch time of about 450ms...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/flames-graph-middle-8374019e.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;Optimizations: 2nd Round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My newly gained speed made me happy, but after looking again into the graph I could still see two call stack spikes which took about the same amount of time, and both ended up re-rendering the CodeMirror instance. So looking a little closely, I could see that the first time was caused by &lt;code&gt;CodeMirror.swapDoc&lt;/code&gt; and the second by &lt;code&gt;CodeMirror.refresh&lt;/code&gt;. When you look at the source code for these two &lt;a href="https://github.com/marijnh/CodeMirror/blob/master/lib/codemirror.js#L3207"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/marijnh/CodeMirror/blob/master/lib/codemirror.js#L3199"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, you can see that they both end up calling the same methods, which results in a complete repaint of CodeMirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand what was happening, I need to explain what happens when you switch a tab. For performance reasons we only keep one CodeMirror instance around and if you switch from one tab to another we call &lt;code&gt;swapDoc&lt;/code&gt; to change the document that is being displayed. To accommodate for size changes and highlighting changes, we call &lt;code&gt;refresh&lt;/code&gt; at the end of the switching process. But with my knowledge that &lt;code&gt;swapDoc&lt;/code&gt; already does everything we need to do, I just moved &lt;code&gt;swapDoc&lt;/code&gt; to the end of the process, (of course there were some other problems that this entailed but it was not too bad) and voila, only one repaint of CodeMirror when switching tabs. Which now gave a switch time of just 167ms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/flames-graph-after-085d5d4c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;#39;ve seen, profiling, measuring and looking at these great data points that the dev tools provide, gives you an easy way to find and track down performance problems. And when you look at this data, it&amp;#39;s immediately clear that it really pays off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st Round&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd Round&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2055ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Support for Parse.com</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/parse-integration/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/09/parse-integration/</id>
    <published>2013-09-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is delighted to announce support for &lt;a href="http://parse.com"&gt;Parse.com&lt;/a&gt;. Developers can now write code in the world's best Web IDE and deploy it directly to Parse.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javascript/Cloud Code  developers will find that they can code and deploy a Parse app incredibly quickly...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is delighted to announce support for &lt;a href="http://parse.com"&gt;Parse.com&lt;/a&gt;. Developers can now write code in the world&amp;#39;s best Web IDE and deploy it directly to Parse.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javascript/Cloud Code  developers will find that they can code and deploy a Parse app incredibly quickly with nothing but a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//player.vimeo.com/video/75482235?autoplay=1&amp;hd=1" target="_blank"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to see a very short video of how incredibly easy it is to build and deploy Cloud Code Apps from Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Application Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application structure in Codio is the same as if you were coding on your local machine. You will also see the global.json file, which is where your application and master keys are specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="parse structure" src="/s/img/blog/parse-structure-6142066f.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Parse.com Deployment Profile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve added a Parse deployment profile into Codio. This lets Codio take care of the entire deployment process onto Parse.com. Watch the video above to see this in action. Deployment is extremely fast as it&amp;#39;s a Cloud-&gt;Cloud operation, with only diffs being transferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="parse structure" src="/s/img/blog/parse-deploy-121d1c0f.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Example Apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are two sample Apps, both of which are standard Parse.com tutorials. You can load them directly into the Codio IDE. Feel free to fork them in Codio (Project-&gt;Fork). You can then follow the instructions in the README.md files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_4"&gt;To Do App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the button below to load this front-end App into Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/192Whma" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src=" https://codio-public.s3.amazonaws.com/sharing/show-me-the-code.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_5"&gt;AnyImg App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the button below to load this Cloud Code back-end app into Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/1eJAHv2)" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src=" https://codio-public.s3.amazonaws.com/sharing/show-me-the-code.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href="/s/docs/deployment/"&gt;read more about deployment&lt;/a&gt; in our documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Creating a Parse.com App&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have set up a Parse.com template. When you go to create a new project from the Codio Dashboard, select &amp;quot;From a template&amp;quot; from the Create Project option dropdown. You&amp;#39;ll find a &amp;quot;Parse Anyimg&amp;quot; template waiting for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the README.md file and follow the instructions to get it running in 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
