<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codio Blog</title>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Command Bar</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/command-bar/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/command-bar/</id>
    <published>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're a Sublime Text user, you'll probably use the Command Palette (&lt;code&gt;Cmd-Shift-P&lt;/code&gt;). This is a great way to access all commands from a single keyboard shortcut rather than digging around and trying to find what you want in all the various menu options...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re a Sublime Text user, you&amp;#39;ll probably use the Command Palette (&lt;code&gt;Cmd-Shift-P&lt;/code&gt;). This is a great way to access all commands from a single keyboard shortcut rather than digging around and trying to find what you want in all the various menu options. And if you don&amp;#39;t know the keyboard shortcut for a particular command, it&amp;#39;s a very fast way of discovering it without searching the menu or docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re excited to tell you that Codio now has its very own &lt;a href="/s/docs/command-bar"&gt;Command Bar&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="command bar" src="/s/img/blog/command-bar-bc6b6d2f.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Cmd+Shift+P&lt;/code&gt; (Mac) or &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shft+P&lt;/code&gt; (PC/Linux) and the Command Bar will appear. Just type any part of the command you&amp;#39;re looking for and the list will narrow down to match your input. Press &lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt; or click on the command and it will be executed instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as being able to access everything you can find in the menu, you can also toggle a few common preferences, and trigger anything that can be accessed by a keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Git and a Tease of what is to Come!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/</id>
    <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning we rolled out a large and quite a significant change to the underlying infrastructure of Codio. For most of you, you won't notice anything different, but it is worth mentioning to you what we changed, how this may affect you, and why we...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning we rolled out a large and quite a significant change to the underlying infrastructure of Codio. For most of you, you won&amp;#39;t notice anything different, but it is worth mentioning to you what we changed, how this may affect you, and why we did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;A Little Background...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is quite a unique beast from your familiar desktop based IDE, and the reason for that is down to the open and collaborative nature of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desktop IDE is designed to be used in a single-user environment. You open a project and code away without any other users seeing what you are doing, or being able to affect what you are doing. Until you pull or push via source control, you are working in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A browser-based IDE like Codio is almost the complete opposite of the above, especially for public projects. A public project is open and readable by anyone, at any time. You could be coding away while several others are reading your code, and if those other users have write access, they will also be editing code. This is great for open source, as it allows a level of collaboration not previously possible on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this introduces some unique challenges for us, especially in the way Git is used. Git is not designed for a multi-user environment. Committing, branching, merging; these are all actions that you run in isolation, safely away from your collaborators. Only when you push, pull or work with remotes do you start to interact with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We initially built in Git support for Codio based on a system of multiple working copies. This meant that each branch used a separate working copy or set of files, and allowed you to work on any branch without affecting or being affected by others. This worked great, but meant we had to wrap some Git commands to allow them to work with these multiple working copies, and that meant we couldn&amp;#39;t provide full Git support without considerable work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;So what changed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came to a realization that we probably over-thought this issue a little, and perhaps even created problems that were not real-word problems in the first place. We listened to you telling us you wanted access to all your favourite Git commands and options. So this morning we removed multiple working copies, and changed all projects to use Git in the way it was designed to be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;How does this affect me?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, probably very little. But it is important to know one simple thing... that now all Git commands will affect all users equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when you checkout a different branch, others on that project will also be switched to use that branch. Which is actually what you would expect to happen anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing here, is that Git now works in a way that you are familiar with, and will allow us to provide full Git support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Why have you done this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me on to the juicy part of this post, and the tease...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is awesome when working on front-end development, but we recognise that when it comes to server-side development, there are a few hoops you have to jump through. We always knew that this would be the case, and that we would need to build out a solution for working on server-side dev. So now that time has come, and this Git change is the first step toward the goal of full-stack development using Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early next year, you will be able to use Codio to build almost any kind of project, from the simplest static site, to the complex; and using almost any language you wish, including NodeJS, PHP, Python and Ruby. Every single Codio project will have its own full-stack development environment in the cloud, meaning that all you need is your browser and Codio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once that is in place, the entire Git tool-set will be available without ever having to leave Codio. You will be able to use Git the way you want, and without any restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Common User Preferences</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/common-preferences/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/common-preferences/</id>
    <published>2013-12-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio already provides a &lt;a href="/s/s/docs/settings-prefs/prefs-list/"&gt;high level of customisation&lt;/a&gt;, because we know that every developer works differently and you all have your own way of working. The &lt;a href="https://codio.com/s/docs/settings-prefs/"&gt;Preferences system&lt;/a&gt; in Codio is based on an INI file, which makes it extremely easy to edit your...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio already provides a &lt;a href="/s/s/docs/settings-prefs/prefs-list/"&gt;high level of customisation&lt;/a&gt;, because we know that every developer works differently and you all have your own way of working. The &lt;a href="https://codio.com/s/docs/settings-prefs/"&gt;Preferences system&lt;/a&gt; in Codio is based on an INI file, which makes it extremely easy to edit your prefs. It&amp;#39;s just like writing code, which of course we all like doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/prefs-8985f8a2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are a few common preferences that tend to get used more than others, so we&amp;#39;ve made these even easier for you to access and edit. Check out the new and improved &lt;code&gt;View&lt;/code&gt; menu. You can now change the following directly from this menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;font size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wrapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;soft tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tab size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio - now even more convenient!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Auto-Complete for Any Language</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/auto-complete-for-any-language/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/auto-complete-for-any-language/</id>
    <published>2013-11-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Up until now, you have been able to use auto-complete for Javascript, HTML and CSS using the keyboard shortcut &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt;. Well now, you can use auto-complete for any language in Codio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio will track common keywords in the file you are editing...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Up until now, you have been able to use auto-complete for Javascript, HTML and CSS using the keyboard shortcut &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt;. Well now, you can use auto-complete for any language in Codio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio will track common keywords in the file you are editing, and provide auto-completion for them all. Just hit &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt; at any time while editing and you will be shown a list of common keywords. And if you type the first few characters of a keyword and hit &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt;, you will be shown matches for the characters you just entered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will soon have the ability to automatically show matches without requiring you to hit the keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_0"&gt;Did you know...?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can customise the auto-complete keyboard shortcut, and in fact any other shortcuts that we provide? Open up your preferences (&lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences&lt;/code&gt;) and simply override any of the default shortcuts with whatever you want. &lt;a href="/s/docs/ide/code-editor/kb-shortcuts/"&gt;Read the docs for more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quick Open</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/quick-open/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/quick-open/</id>
    <published>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick open (default is &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt;) also known as fast open, is a great way of opening files without the need to access the file tree. Press &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt; or select &lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt;Open File&lt;/code&gt; from the menu and the quick open dialog will appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quick open" src="/s/img/blog/quick-open-1fbc5512.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick open (default is &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt;) also known as fast open, is a great way of opening files without the need to access the file tree. Press &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt; or select &lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt;Open File&lt;/code&gt; from the menu and the quick open dialog will appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quick open" src="/s/img/blog/quick-open-1fbc5512.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now start typing the name of a file and as you type, the list will be filtered. You can then select the file you want using the mouse or use the keyboard, pressing &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; on the required file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Selective File Deployment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-specific-files/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-specific-files/</id>
    <published>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although we like to push RSYNC as the fastest way of working with Codio, there are many users who want to work with hosting providers that only provide FTP access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have added a new feature that lets you choose what files or folders...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although we like to push RSYNC as the fastest way of working with Codio, there are many users who want to work with hosting providers that only provide FTP access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have added a new feature that lets you choose what files or folders to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to deploy selectively&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;select any files or folders in the file tree and then right-click and select the Deploy option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;right click in the tab above the file you are editing and do the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="specific files" src="/s/img/blog/deploy-specific-4a409df2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Codio is cloud based and your target FTP server probably is, too, this deployment will be very fast, so developing like this is perfectly possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
