<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Code and Unload by Codio</title>
  <subtitle>While we code we often have lots of ideas brewing around. Ideas we'd like to unload onto you</subtitle>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Codio:Annotations - Say it with a sample</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/say-it-with-a-sample/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/say-it-with-a-sample/</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we were building the Codio IDE, we suddenly realized that we have in our hands a unique platform that helps people explain code - any programming language, any skill level, not just beginners. It is ideal for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;development tutorials (any skill...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we were building the Codio IDE, we suddenly realized that we have in our hands a unique platform that helps people explain code - any programming language, any skill level, not just beginners. It is ideal for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;development tutorials (any skill level)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API samples and explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer documentation samples and tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documenting and explaining advanced frameworks, libraries etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example code projects of any sort and any level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Tell us what you think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will offer this as a completely free platform, but it will require real effort a) to add the Annotation features and b) to provide the infrastructure. It is really important to us to know that people are behind our efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you like what you see, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio is an awesome platform for code examples and tutorials, any language, any skill level" target="_blank"&gt;tweet about us&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/CodioHQ" target="_blank"&gt;like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or just leave a comment at the bottom of this page. The more support we get for this, the more we&amp;#39;ll throw at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Getting behind Education&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our real hopes is that Codio provides a new way for schools, universities and other programming courses to teach, based on working real working code, and in a way that does not require the learner to assemble a full development stack before being able to start tinkering. By offering these features and a real Web IDE for free, we hope to clear away a few obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Video Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post describes things step by step, but if you prefer a video run-through, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/ypR9CUG1Tjo?autoplay=1&amp;hd=1&amp;fs=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;rel=0&amp;"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;What&amp;#39;s missing from most tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know what most tutorials look like. It doesn&amp;#39;t matter if it is a tutorial for a complete newbie or something that is explaining a complex framework, API or library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is an example of a high quality tutorial from webplatform.org, which you can scroll through or you can &lt;a href="http://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/tutorials/creating_and_modifying_html" target="_blank"&gt;open the full page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style="width:700px; height:400px" src="http://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/tutorials/creating_and_modifying_html"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very well written indeed, but there is a lot to digest here, and this is usually the case with web and video tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am learning about a something new, there are two things I always yearn for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the tutorial seamlessly wrapped up with a &lt;strong&gt;real, fully working code example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interactivity - being able to run, explore, fork, edit etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... and this is exactly what Codio:Annotations offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;The same tutorial run in Codio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;#39;s see how Codio can change the approach to the same tutorial&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;Better - Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can load any development project already today. Just include a link (&lt;a href="https://codio.com/fmay/HTML-Create-and-Modify/tree/App/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;try clicking here&lt;/a&gt;) from within your page or use a Codio widget to go to the project. Try it out and see what it feels like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codio.com/fmay/HTML-Create-and-Modify/tree/App/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/codio-widget.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Better - Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are lots of sitations where I want to make things even more seamless and avoid having to leave the tutorial page. You can embed the Codio IDE straight into your web page as shown below. It&amp;#39;s a simple project, but have a quick explore ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style="width:800px; height:600px" src="https://codio.com/fmay/HTML-Create-and-Modify/tree/App/index.html"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Codio IDE, your sample can be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;viewed and explored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forked and edited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;downloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run (if it is an HTML5+CSS+JS project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_7"&gt;Better - Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following steps have not been built yet, but will be with your support. The screenshots below are mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine being able to explore the code freely by clicking on the icons within the IDE wherever you see one. I will explain further down how this can all be set up in your source project using your regular IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-settabfromlink-0556a452.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see rich text (as shown), images, audio or video depending on the icon you click on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_8"&gt;Better - Step 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to, I can put the entire tutorial itself into the project and then get a guided tour through the code, either by click on the navigation buttons ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-guided-14be20a3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... or by scrolling through the embedded tutorial, which syncs automatically with the associated piece of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-scroll-1-fee244fe.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_9"&gt;Better - Step 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final piece in the jigsaw is also really important - how to find great tutorials. We will build a curated area where each tutorial can be posted. Anyone who has built one can&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;post it to a language area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and within that a subject matter area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allow users to vote on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encourage users to post comments to other learners and to the author so it can be improved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will look something like this ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/exp-curation-673c9711.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_10"&gt;How does a developer build a Codio tutorial?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make this as easy and unobtrusive as possible. Here are the key points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it should work for any programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you should be able create the content from absolutely any IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it should not mess up your source code or interfere with the way you would want to write code naturally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you should be able to import effortlessly from a ZIP file, Git or Mercurial repo so that future modifications and updates are a no-brainer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshot below shows how tokens are added into the source file ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/ks-tokens-b588e5f7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this one shows how you construct the annotations file. This provides both guided tours, scrolling as well as the project structure annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example Annotation" src="/s/img/blog/ks-annotation-file-57356095.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="support"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_11"&gt;Please support us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you agree that Codio is a force for good whether in Education or for professional development, then doing any of the following will really help us know we are pointed in the right direction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio is an awesome platform for code examples and tutorials, any language, any skill level" target="_blank"&gt;Tweet your support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/CodioHQ" target="_blank"&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a comment at the bottom of this page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just let others know about Codio:Annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Drag and Drop in the File Explorer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/drag-and-drop-in-the-file-explorer/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/04/drag-and-drop-in-the-file-explorer/</id>
    <published>2013-04-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We just rolled out a really helpful new feature that will allow you to move files and directories around in your projects. Simply drag any file or directory within your project's file explorer, and drop it into any other place within the explorer.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We just rolled out a really helpful new feature that will allow you to move files and directories around in your projects. Simply drag any file or directory within your project&amp;#39;s file explorer, and drop it into any other place within the explorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Drag and Drop in the File Explorer" src="/s/img/blog/drag-drop-explorer-e50379de.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, peasy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Teaching to Code, Learning to Code</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-for-education/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-for-education/</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having watched the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/nKIu9yen5nc"&gt;code.org video&lt;/a&gt; and seen what they are trying to achieve, we wondered how cool it would be if we could contribute to this initiative in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we can. We have a great Web IDE and with a little effort, we've...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having watched the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/nKIu9yen5nc"&gt;code.org video&lt;/a&gt; and seen what they are trying to achieve, we wondered how cool it would be if we could contribute to this initiative in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we can. We have a great Web IDE and with a little effort, we&amp;#39;ve got a game changer for the way tutorials, documentation and code samples are delivered. We want this to be a free, web based platform that let&amp;#39;s any author of code examples or tutorials deliver their content in a natural way, that doesn&amp;#39;t dumb anything down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get you interested, take a look below. It&amp;#39;s a real and fully functioning IDE. It&amp;#39;s fast, doesn&amp;#39;t require signup, can be embedded anywhere and is being aggressively developed. However, as a vehicle for providing working code tutorials and examples, it&amp;#39;s a great start. Once we&amp;#39;ve added our annotation features, we think it&amp;#39;ll be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, &lt;a href="https://codio.com/fmay/Impress/tree/Impress/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to see the IDE full size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="950" height="600" src="https://codio.com/fmay/Impress/tree/Impress/index.html" style="margin:20px 0;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of months (with some &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio%20web%20platform%20turns%20your%20%23code%20into%20interactive%20tutorials%20%26%20code%20samples.%20%20https%3A%2F%2Fcodio.com%2Fs%2Fblog%2F2013%2F03%2Fcodio-for-education%2F%20-%20gr8%20for%20%23Education%20%26%20%23developers%20" target="_blank"&gt;verbal encouragement&lt;/a&gt; from the community) we&amp;#39;ll be adding a lot of very cool stuff to Codio, so people can teach and learn in code&amp;#39;s natural home - the IDE. You&amp;#39;ll be able to add guided tours, rich text explanations that pop-up as you explore the project, audio, and even videos that [for example] show screen output when a piece of code executes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll be able to set this all up from your own IDE as well as within Codio, and it will not interfere with or mess up your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;What&amp;#39;s the problem with online tutorials?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say &lt;strong&gt;tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;, I don&amp;#39;t mean novice developer tutorials, but also advanced APIs, frameworks, libraries or products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The natural environment for a code project or example is an IDE, but tutorials are forced to show code snippets - often lots of them. A bit like &lt;a href="http://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/tutorials/creating_and_modifying_html" target="_blank"&gt;this top quality tutorial&lt;/a&gt; from webplatform.org. This can mean a lot of mental gymnastics as you read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m learning, there isn&amp;#39;t usually any &lt;strong&gt;instant&lt;/strong&gt; access to a full, working project, and if there is, it has to be downloaded and installed somewhere. Again, what we would love is instant access to an online or even embedded IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I usually find myself wanting to run the project, then make my own modifications and run it again. Experiment in other words. You rarely have this facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If these problems were solved, with interactivity at the heart of it, it would significantly speed up the way new coding material is absorbed and taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Codio:Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s what we&amp;#39;re calling all this. We&amp;#39;re going to make the whole teaching/learning process highly interactive and fun for the learners and the authors. Learners will get either guided tours around the project, or be able to explore the code freely, and get information wherever they are looking. We&amp;#39;ll have more details very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few key points about the platform:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s a web platform, so instantly accessible for learners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors and learners can access without needing to signup (no nasty dialogs or screens before you see the code).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no commercial catch - any public tutorial or example is, and always will be, free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s great for absolutely any programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has to work beautifully for school pupils, but equally great for highly advanced stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will be a great way of adding code samples into any form of API or developer documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Give us some encouragement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like what you are reading, we ask that you encourage us in any way that you feel will help. The best way is to let others know. We&amp;#39;re a small company and doing this requires a fair bit of effort. So feel free to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio%20web%20platform%20turns%20your%20%23code%20into%20interactive%20tutorials%20%26%20code%20samples.%20%20https%3A%2F%2Fcodio.com%2Fs%2Fblog%2F2013%2F03%2Fcodio-for-education%2F%20-%20gr8%20for%20%23Education%20%26%20%23developers%20" target=" target="_blank"&gt;tweet something nice!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building with Grunt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/building-with-grunt/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/building-with-grunt/</id>
    <published>2013-03-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gruntjs.com/"&gt;Grunt&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely useful tool that any self-respecting front-end developer should have in his/her arsenal. At Codio, we use it to concatenate, minify, lint, compile and build our client side code ready for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of last Friday's...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gruntjs.com/"&gt;Grunt&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely useful tool that any self-respecting front-end developer should have in his/her arsenal. At Codio, we use it to concatenate, minify, lint, compile and build our client side code ready for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of last Friday&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/our-twenty-percent-time/"&gt;weekly hack day&lt;/a&gt;, I spent the day upgrading our Grunt installation and our custom tasks to the latest 0.4 version. So I thought I&amp;#39;d write a short article on what Grunt is and how we use it at Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;What is Grunt?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a Javascript task runner, which simply means you can use it to automate your most mundane and common development and build tasks. The less work you have to do when performing repetitive tasks like minification, compilation, unit testing, linting, etc, the easier your job becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since version 0.4, Grunt has really matured and come out of its shell, and now boasts a large ecosystem of plugins that can help you automate pretty much anything you want. And if you don&amp;#39;t find a plugin that does what you want, it&amp;#39;s extremely easy to write one yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;How to install Grunt?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grunt runs on &lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/"&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt;, and is installed and managed via &lt;a href="https://npmjs.org/"&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt;. So if you haven&amp;#39;t already, make sure you have both those installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Grunt, just use NPM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -g grunt-cli
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will give you a handy little &lt;code&gt;grunt&lt;/code&gt; command, which you will use to run your Grunt tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Preparing your Project for Grunt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical setup will require two files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;package.json&lt;/strong&gt; - This file is used by NPM to manage your projects dependencies, and is also used by Grunt to manage its dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gruntfile.js&lt;/strong&gt; - This is where you define and configure your tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new file in the root of your project called &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;my-project-name&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.1.0&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;devDependencies&amp;quot;: {
    &amp;quot;grunt&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;~0.4.1&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;grunt-contrib-uglify&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;~0.2.0&amp;quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tells NPM that we depend on the &lt;code&gt;grunt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;grunt-contrib-uglify&lt;/code&gt; packages. Running the following will install these dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now create your &lt;code&gt;Gruntfile.js&lt;/code&gt;, which also belongs in the root of your project alongside &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;. Fill the file with the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;module.exports = function(grunt) {

  // Project configuration.
  grunt.initConfig({
    uglify: {
      build: {
        src: &amp;#39;src/script.js&amp;#39;,
        dest: &amp;#39;build/script.min.js&amp;#39;
      }
    }
  });

  // Load the plugin that provides the &amp;quot;uglify&amp;quot; task.
  grunt.loadNpmTasks(&amp;#39;grunt-contrib-uglify&amp;#39;);

  // Default task(s).
  grunt.registerTask(&amp;#39;default&amp;#39;, [&amp;#39;uglify&amp;#39;]);

};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets run through this file from top to bottom...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 4&lt;/strong&gt; is where we set define our configuration for the tasks we want to use. Each top level element defines a task. In our example, we have just one task &lt;code&gt;uglify&lt;/code&gt;, which simply takes the value of &lt;code&gt;build.src&lt;/code&gt;, runs it through the Uglify lib and places its output in a new file as specified with the value of &lt;code&gt;buil.dest&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grunt.initConfig({
  uglify: {
    build: {
      src: &amp;#39;src/script.js&amp;#39;,
      dest: &amp;#39;build/script.min.js&amp;#39;
    }
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 14&lt;/strong&gt; tells Grunt to load the &lt;code&gt;grunt-contrib-uglify&lt;/code&gt; task from the NPM package specified in our &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then finally on &lt;strong&gt;line 17&lt;/strong&gt;, we create a new &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; task, which is simply an alias for the &lt;code&gt;uglify&lt;/code&gt; task. The &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; task will be run if you don&amp;#39;t specify any task on the command line. So the following three commands are now identical:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grunt uglify
grunt default
grunt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grunt has a great ecosystem of open source plugins, and a place to &lt;a href="http://gruntjs.com/plugins"&gt;find and search for the plugin you want&lt;/a&gt;. I strongly recommend that you take a look through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully from this simple example, you can see how easy and powerful Grunt can be. It&amp;#39;s also worth noting that we have plans to implement a similar task based system directly into Codio. So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our 20% Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/our-twenty-percent-time/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/our-twenty-percent-time/</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, for the very first time, the Codio engineering team will be trying something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is famous for allowing and indeed encouraging its engineers to use 20% of their time to work on anything that they want. This 20% allowance has resulted...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, for the very first time, the Codio engineering team will be trying something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is famous for allowing and indeed encouraging its engineers to use 20% of their time to work on anything that they want. This 20% allowance has resulted in Gmail and other popular Google products. So we wanted to try something similar by encouraging our engineers to work on anything that they want. The only proviso is that it must be something related to Codio itself, or something that will benefit the team with their work on Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow and then every Friday after, we will be working on whatever the hell we want!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s exciting and I&amp;#39;m hoping to be able to take part myself as I don&amp;#39;t get to do much coding these days. If just one new feature or small bug fix comes out of these, I think it will still be deemed a success. This is not only a way to discover and build new features for Codio, but also as a bonding exercise within the team, and a way to have a little fun with something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also a great excuse to be free from the daily constraints of picking and working on tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll be sure to let you all know how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Collaboration in Coding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/collaboration-in-coding/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/collaboration-in-coding/</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you should already know by now, we &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; Codio into public beta yesterday. It's an all new cloud based IDE, and it will be the very first cloud based IDE that every developer will love to use, day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We live not in a passive society...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you should already know by now, we &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; Codio into public beta yesterday. It&amp;#39;s an all new cloud based IDE, and it will be the very first cloud based IDE that every developer will love to use, day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We live not in a passive society, a read-only society, but in a writable society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is the very first thing we thought about when we first sat down to plan Codio, and has continued to be at the very heart of almost everything we are building since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is arguably the single biggest advantage when using software in the browser, because the browser is constantly connected via the internet, and because the browser is now the most used application on almost any device. Collaboration is also hugely important when writing software and especially when building for the web. It empowers us to do more, while remaining in the [virtual] company of our friends and colleague&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of collaborating between you and others when using the browser and the internet are zero. Email, Twitter, Skype - these are all free to use, and they are all about collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It is the long history of humankind (and animal kind, too) those who learned to collaborate and improvise most effectively have prevailed.&amp;quot; - Charles Darwin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, but now I hear a few of you asking the question &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;what if I don&amp;#39;t have anyone to collaborate with?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;. The answer to that is easy and simple... &lt;strong&gt;you do!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is full of like-minded people just like you. People who love building web apps, designing web sites, or creating mobile applications. And they all have something to share, even you! And whether you realise it or not, you co-ordinate and collaborate every single day, with people you have never met or spoken to before. No matter what accomplishments you make, odds are somebody helped you along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The largest sites are essentially all about encouraging collaboration and making it easier for us to co-ordinate with each other. Sites and apps like Facebook, Twitter, Gmail, Wikipedia, Github, Basecamp, and now Codio are leading the way here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; powerful, and we think you&amp;#39;ll love what you can already do with Codio. If you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codiohq"&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;#39;ll let you know every time we increase our levels of collaboration within Codio, because we have loads more planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few posts, I will be detailing just how Codio can help improve collaboration for you and your team.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
