<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Code and Unload by Codio</title>
  <subtitle>While we code we often have lots of ideas brewing around. Ideas we'd like to unload onto you</subtitle>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Teaching to Code, Learning to Code</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-for-education/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-for-education/</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having watched the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/nKIu9yen5nc"&gt;code.org video&lt;/a&gt; and seen what they are trying to achieve, we wandered how cool it would be if we could contribute to this initiative in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we can. We have a great Web IDE and with a little effort, we've...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having watched the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/nKIu9yen5nc"&gt;code.org video&lt;/a&gt; and seen what they are trying to achieve, we wandered how cool it would be if we could contribute to this initiative in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we can. We have a great Web IDE and with a little effort, we&amp;#39;ve got a game changer for the way tutorials, documentation and code samples are delivered. We want this to be a free, web based platform that let&amp;#39;s any author of code examples or tutorials deliver their content in a natural way, that doesn&amp;#39;t dumb anything down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get you interested, take a look below. It&amp;#39;s a real and fully functioning IDE. It&amp;#39;s fast, doesn&amp;#39;t require signup, can be embedded anywhere and is being aggressively developed. However, as a vehicle for providing working code tutorials and examples, it&amp;#39;s a great start. Once we&amp;#39;ve added our annotation features, we think it&amp;#39;ll be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="950" height="600" src="https://codio.com/fmay/Impress/tree/Impress/index.html" style="margin:20px 0;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of months (with some &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio%20web%20platform%20turns%20your%20%23code%20into%20interactive%20tutorials%20%26%20code%20samples.%20%20https%3A%2F%2Fcodio.com%2Fblog%2F2013%2F03%2Fcodio-for-education%2F.%20Gr8%20for%20%23Education%20%26%20%23developers%20" target="_blank"&gt;verbal encouragement&lt;/a&gt; from the community) we&amp;#39;ll be adding a lot of very cool stuff to Codio, so people can teach and learn in code&amp;#39;s natural home - the IDE. You&amp;#39;ll be able to add guided tours, rich text explanations that pop-up as you explore the project, audio, and even videos that [for example] show screen output when a piece of code executes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll be able to set this all up from your own IDE as well as within Codio, and it will not interfere with or mess up your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;What&amp;#39;s the problem with online tutorials?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say &lt;strong&gt;tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;, I don&amp;#39;t mean novice developer tutorials, but also advanced APIs, frameworks, libraries or products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The natural environment for a code project or example is an IDE, but tutorials are forced to show code snippets - often lots of them. A bit like &lt;a href="http://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/tutorials/creating_and_modifying_html" target="_blank"&gt;this top quality tutorial&lt;/a&gt; from webplatform.org. This can mean a lot of mental gymnastics as you read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m learning, there isn&amp;#39;t usually any &lt;strong&gt;instant&lt;/strong&gt; access to a full, working project, and if there is, it has to be downloaded and installed somewhere. Again, what we would love is instant access to an online or even embedded IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I usually find myself wanting to run the project, then make my own modifications and run it again. Experiment in other words. You rarely have this facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If these problems were solved, with interactivity at the heart of it, it would significantly speed up the way new coding material is absorbed and taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Codio:Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s what we&amp;#39;re calling all this. We&amp;#39;re going to make the whole teaching/learning process highly interactive and fun for the learners and the authors. Learners will get either guided tours around the project, or be able to explore the code freely, and get information wherever they are looking. We&amp;#39;ll have more details very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few key points about the platform:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s a web platform, so instantly accessible for learners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors and learners can access without needing to signup (no nasty dialogs or screens before you see the code).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no commercial catch - any public tutorial or example is, and always will be, free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s great for absolutely any programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has to work beautifully for school pupils, but equally great for highly advanced stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will be a great way of adding code samples into any form of API or developer documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Give us some encouragement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like what you are reading, we ask that you encourage us in any way that you feel will help. The best way is to let others know. We&amp;#39;re a small company and doing this requires a fair bit of effort. So feel free to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/home/?status=Codio%20web%20platform%20turns%20your%20%23code%20into%20interactive%20tutorials%20%26%20code%20samples.%20%20https%3A%2F%2Fcodio.com%2Fblog%2F2013%2F03%2Fcodio-for-education%2F.%20Gr8%20for%20%23Education%20%26%20%23developers%20" target=" target="_blank"&gt;tweet something nice!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building with Grunt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/building-with-grunt/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/building-with-grunt/</id>
    <published>2013-03-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gruntjs.com/"&gt;Grunt&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely useful tool that any self-respecting front-end developer should have in his/her arsenal. At Codio, we use it to concatenate, minify, lint, compile and build our client side code ready for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of last Friday's...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gruntjs.com/"&gt;Grunt&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely useful tool that any self-respecting front-end developer should have in his/her arsenal. At Codio, we use it to concatenate, minify, lint, compile and build our client side code ready for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of last Friday&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/our-twenty-percent-time/"&gt;weekly hack day&lt;/a&gt;, I spent the day upgrading our Grunt installation and our custom tasks to the latest 0.4 version. So I thought I&amp;#39;d write a short article on what Grunt is and how we use it at Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;What is Grunt?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a Javascript task runner, which simply means you can use it to automate your most mundane and common development and build tasks. The less work you have to do when performing repetitive tasks like minification, compilation, unit testing, linting, etc, the easier your job becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since version 0.4, Grunt has really matured and come out of its shell, and now boasts a large ecosystem of plugins that can help you automate pretty much anything you want. And if you don&amp;#39;t find a plugin that does what you want, it&amp;#39;s extremely easy to write one yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;How to install Grunt?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grunt runs on &lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/"&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt;, and is installed and managed via &lt;a href="https://npmjs.org/"&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt;. So if you haven&amp;#39;t already, make sure you have both those installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Grunt, just use NPM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -g grunt-cli
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will give you a handy little &lt;code&gt;grunt&lt;/code&gt; command, which you will use to run your Grunt tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Preparing your Project for Grunt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical setup will require two files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;package.json&lt;/strong&gt; - This file is used by NPM to manage your projects dependencies, and is also used by Grunt to manage its dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gruntfile.js&lt;/strong&gt; - This is where you define and configure your tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new file in the root of your project called &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;my-project-name&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.1.0&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;devDependencies&amp;quot;: {
    &amp;quot;grunt&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;~0.4.1&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;grunt-contrib-uglify&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;~0.2.0&amp;quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tells NPM that we depend on the &lt;code&gt;grunt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;grunt-contrib-uglify&lt;/code&gt; packages. Running the following will install these dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now create your &lt;code&gt;Gruntfile.js&lt;/code&gt;, which also belongs in the root of your project alongside &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;. Fill the file with the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;module.exports = function(grunt) {

  // Project configuration.
  grunt.initConfig({
    uglify: {
      build: {
        src: &amp;#39;src/script.js&amp;#39;,
        dest: &amp;#39;build/script.min.js&amp;#39;
      }
    }
  });

  // Load the plugin that provides the &amp;quot;uglify&amp;quot; task.
  grunt.loadNpmTasks(&amp;#39;grunt-contrib-uglify&amp;#39;);

  // Default task(s).
  grunt.registerTask(&amp;#39;default&amp;#39;, [&amp;#39;uglify&amp;#39;]);

};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets run through this file from top to bottom...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 4&lt;/strong&gt; is where we set define our configuration for the tasks we want to use. Each top level element defines a task. In our example, we have just one task &lt;code&gt;uglify&lt;/code&gt;, which simply takes the value of &lt;code&gt;build.src&lt;/code&gt;, runs it through the Uglify lib and places its output in a new file as specified with the value of &lt;code&gt;buil.dest&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grunt.initConfig({
  uglify: {
    build: {
      src: &amp;#39;src/script.js&amp;#39;,
      dest: &amp;#39;build/script.min.js&amp;#39;
    }
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 14&lt;/strong&gt; tells Grunt to load the &lt;code&gt;grunt-contrib-uglify&lt;/code&gt; task from the NPM package specified in our &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then finally on &lt;strong&gt;line 17&lt;/strong&gt;, we create a new &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; task, which is simply an alias for the &lt;code&gt;uglify&lt;/code&gt; task. The &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; task will be run if you don&amp;#39;t specify any task on the command line. So the following three commands are now identical:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grunt uglify
grunt default
grunt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grunt has a great ecosystem of open source plugins, and a place to &lt;a href="http://gruntjs.com/plugins"&gt;find and search for the plugin you want&lt;/a&gt;. I strongly recommend that you take a look through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully from this simple example, you can see how easy and powerful Grunt can be. It&amp;#39;s also worth noting that we have plans to implement a similar task based system directly into Codio. So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our 20% Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/our-twenty-percent-time/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/our-twenty-percent-time/</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, for the very first time, the Codio engineering team will be trying something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is famous for allowing and indeed encouraging its engineers to use 20% of their time to work on anything that they want. This 20% allowance has resulted...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, for the very first time, the Codio engineering team will be trying something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is famous for allowing and indeed encouraging its engineers to use 20% of their time to work on anything that they want. This 20% allowance has resulted in Gmail and other popular Google products. So we wanted to try something similar by encouraging our engineers to work on anything that they want. The only proviso is that it must be something related to Codio itself, or something that will benefit the team with their work on Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow and then every Friday after, we will be working on whatever the hell we want!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s exciting and I&amp;#39;m hoping to be able to take part myself as I don&amp;#39;t get to do much coding these days. If just one new feature or small bug fix comes out of these, I think it will still be deemed a success. This is not only a way to discover and build new features for Codio, but also as a bonding exercise within the team, and a way to have a little fun with something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also a great excuse to be free from the daily constraints of picking and working on tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll be sure to let you all know how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Collaboration in Coding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/collaboration-in-coding/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/collaboration-in-coding/</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you should already know by now, we &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; Codio into public beta yesterday. It's an all new cloud based IDE, and it will be the very first cloud based IDE that every developer will love to use, day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We live not in a passive society...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you should already know by now, we &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; Codio into public beta yesterday. It&amp;#39;s an all new cloud based IDE, and it will be the very first cloud based IDE that every developer will love to use, day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We live not in a passive society, a read-only society, but in a writable society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is the very first thing we thought about when we first sat down to plan Codio, and has continued to be at the very heart of almost everything we are building since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is arguably the single biggest advantage when using software in the browser, because the browser is constantly connected via the internet, and because the browser is now the most used application on almost any device. Collaboration is also hugely important when writing software and especially when building for the web. It empowers us to do more, while remaining in the [virtual] company of our friends and colleague&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of collaborating between you and others when using the browser and the internet are zero. Email, Twitter, Skype - these are all free to use, and they are all about collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It is the long history of humankind (and animal kind, too) those who learned to collaborate and improvise most effectively have prevailed.&amp;quot; - Charles Darwin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, but now I hear a few of you asking the question &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;what if I don&amp;#39;t have anyone to collaborate with?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;. The answer to that is easy and simple... &lt;strong&gt;you do!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is full of like-minded people just like you. People who love building web apps, designing web sites, or creating mobile applications. And they all have something to share, even you! And whether you realise it or not, you co-ordinate and collaborate every single day, with people you have never met or spoken to before. No matter what accomplishments you make, odds are somebody helped you along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The largest sites are essentially all about encouraging collaboration and making it easier for us to co-ordinate with each other. Sites and apps like Facebook, Twitter, Gmail, Wikipedia, Github, Basecamp, and now Codio are leading the way here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; powerful, and we think you&amp;#39;ll love what you can already do with Codio. If you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codiohq"&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;#39;ll let you know every time we increase our levels of collaboration within Codio, because we have loads more planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few posts, I will be detailing just how Codio can help improve collaboration for you and your team.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We're Hiring Frontend Engineers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/we-are-hiring-engineers/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/we-are-hiring-engineers/</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now we have the &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"&gt;beta out the door&lt;/a&gt;, it's time to concentrate on the future of Codio and working towards that perfect IDE. But we need some additional help from an experienced front-end engineer who want to be part of something truly exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now we have the &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"&gt;beta out the door&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#39;s time to concentrate on the future of Codio and working towards that perfect IDE. But we need some additional help from an experienced front-end engineer who want to be part of something truly exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of our front-end engineers, you&amp;#39;ll be responsible for building arguably the most important part of Codio. The IDE itself is a single page app built using the latest Javascript, HTML5 and CSS3 technologies. We hate IE and love any browser which sits on the cutting edge of the web, so you will be encouraged to play with and implement the latest and greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are also our target market for the product itself, which makes it an extremely attractive and exciting product to work on. You&amp;#39;ve most likely heard this said before, but we really do have something that is built for developers, and by developers. We want you to be happy to use Codio as your day to day IDE, and if you aren&amp;#39;t, help us to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want someone who is free thinking, passionate and has a love of what they do. If you find yourself still hacking away at 4am without realising the time, then you&amp;#39;re the kind of person we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;What we want from you:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3+ years professional experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience and knowledge of Javascript (including jQuery), HTML5 and CSS3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition of the benefits of test driven development and well tested code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of the browser market and its changing pace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An eye for detail, both in your code and in the browser. Developers can be a picky bunch you know ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common sense when it comes to UI and UX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work well in a team and on your own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A love of open source software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;You&amp;#39;ll be at an advantage if you also:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have an eye for good design, and experience with Photoshop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy writing, blogging and speaking at tech conferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have experience with Java.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute or have created any open source software (big brownie points for this one).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re a distributed team with our HQ in the UK, so you will be able to work from anywhere you please. We would prefer if you were UK or European based, but if you&amp;#39;re really good, we don&amp;#39;t care where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;To Apply&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop us an email at &lt;a href="mailto:work@codio.com"&gt;work@codio.com&lt;/a&gt; telling us why we should hire you, along with your resume/CV if you have one. Although we&amp;#39;d be much more interested in your Github profile, which speaks volumes about you and what you are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please let me know in the blog comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codio is Live and Kicking!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/</id>
    <published>2013-03-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce the immediate availability of Codio in public beta. This means you can play with what will become the world's very first IDE that addresses all aspects of the HTML5 development life-cycle right now! We're building...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce the immediate availability of Codio in public beta. This means you can play with what will become the world&amp;#39;s very first IDE that addresses all aspects of the HTML5 development life-cycle right now! We&amp;#39;re building an IDE that any developer will want and enjoy using every single day, because there is currently no such thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don&amp;#39;t take my word for it. &lt;strong&gt;Just click the &amp;quot;Create &amp;amp; Play!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; link at the top of the page to create your first Codio project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Codio IDE" src="/s/img/blog/ide-68ac0fff.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a hard and arduous road, but we&amp;#39;re finally at the start of it. Yes I did say the start, and that&amp;#39;s because we have so much more to come. Building the perfect IDE is no small task you know, but what we&amp;#39;re releasing today is the foundation that will set up that which is to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the press release and subscribe to this blog to stay informed...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Codio today announced its launch in public beta, giving developers of all skill levels access to a powerful, web-based visual IDE for HTML5+CSS+JS development. More than a typical code editor, Codio covers the complete web development cycle, from prototype to deployment. It offers novice developers a barrier free way to learn how to build web applications, but is also targeted very much at professional web developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is a lot of stuff to install, setup and configure before you can write a single line of code. We feel that  there is no good reason for this and even developers, who deal with complexity on a daily basis, don’t like to waste  time. Modern web applications have raised expectations significantly with respect to usability and a web based approach to web development opens up lots of exciting new possibilities. Ultimately, coding should be fun and a happy developer produces happy code!” says CEO Freddy May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evolution of the web has witnessed paradigm shifts in new web technologies. The demand and popularity of web app development has, consequently, secured HTML5, CSS and JavaScript its place among the most popular development  languages. As a large number of modern applications now run in browsers, these technologies have become an integral part of most software development projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By concentrating specifically on HTML5, CSS and JavaScript we can focus on the largest part of the developer ecosystem. This allows us constantly to add significant value that would otherwise not be possible if we were to try to cater for all languages,” says May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the era of the cloud it is logical that web applications should not just run on the web, but also be built on the web. Codio offers developers an efficient, modern, and secure IDE whose code is accessible anywhere online via Codio workspaces and shareable with others in a similar way to Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio makes getting started very simple by allowing developers to use it without even signing up. It offers a comfortable environment not just for code editing but also deployment, collaboration, Git and Mercurial integration, as well as support for derivative languages such as Coffeescript, SCSS, LESS all without the need to install, configure and maintain hardware and software stacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio also brings enhanced collaboration to developers. Traditionally, developers collaborate using web based code repositories such as Github and Bitbucket. Codio supports Source Control Management but also adds real time code editing by multiple developers rather like Google Docs. Text chat, voice chat and video are also planned for later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is being aggressively developed and many new features will be appearing on a continuous deployment basis. Some notable features on the horizon are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-pane code editing&lt;br&gt;
Development, staging, production deployment targets&lt;br&gt;
WYSIWYG GUI editor&lt;br&gt;
Interactive code documentation for teaching&lt;br&gt;
Instant preview&lt;br&gt;
Version control&lt;br&gt;
Node.js support&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is expected to come out of Public Beta in middle of 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
