<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codio Blog</title>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>SSH Public Key Management</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/ssh-public-keys/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/ssh-public-keys/</id>
    <published>2013-11-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our focus is to make all aspects of the development process as smooth and easy as it possibly can be. One small but great example of something that is a real pain in the ass is the business of deploying public keys to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Why are they...&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our focus is to make all aspects of the development process as smooth and easy as it possibly can be. One small but great example of something that is a real pain in the ass is the business of deploying public keys to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Why are they needed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio has two main features that require access to remote servers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH Terminal - you can create and manage any number of remote servers directly from Codio. There&amp;#39;s a &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/11/ssh/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on this and you can also &lt;a href="/s/docs/ssh"&gt;read the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying via SFTP and RSYNC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most developers prefer to use SSH to access remote servers, as it avoids password entry completely and is more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio generates public keys that can be found in the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Account&lt;/code&gt; menu. One way of getting your Codio public key on to the remote server is to copy it and then SSH into your remote server and then add it to your &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/authorized_keys&lt;/code&gt; file. However, this is an unnecessary chore. We&amp;#39;ve made it so you can now upload your keys in 2 ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;From your Account dialog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshot below shows how you just need to press the Upload Public Key button and that&amp;#39;s it. You will be asked to enter your access details and that&amp;#39;s it. You can access this dialog via the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Account&lt;/code&gt; menu item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="public key account" src="/s/img/blog/key-account-def388c9.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;From the SSH Connection Manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can SSH into any remote server right from within Codio. In the connections listing, there&amp;#39;s a button you can press that does the same thing as above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="public key account" src="/s/img/blog/key-ssh-6b731019.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Deploy &amp; Preview</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-preview/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-preview/</id>
    <published>2013-11-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are constantly looking to streamline your development process when working in Codio, and this time we focused on the ease with which you can deploy and preview code, and in particular back-end code, such as PHP, NodeJS and Python. We've made some...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are constantly looking to streamline your development process when working in Codio, and this time we focused on the ease with which you can deploy and preview code, and in particular back-end code, such as PHP, NodeJS and Python. We&amp;#39;ve made some changes to the way to preview your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Deploying &amp;amp; Previewing Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s say that you make a small modification to a Node or PHP file, and you then want to preview it. All you now need to do is to press the new &lt;code&gt;Preview&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Deploy &amp;amp; Preview&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;Shift-F9&lt;/code&gt;) button in the menu bar and changes get deployed and previewed in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="deploy-preview" src="/s/img/blog/deploy-preview-1-6954e74e.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve added a few extra options to this new button that can be accessed vis the buttons dropdown menu. These options can change the behaviour of the button to help create a workflow suited to your needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy before Preview&lt;/strong&gt; - Deploys your project immediately before previewing. This works perfectlt with the Rsync deployment type, as only modified files will get deployed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy in a Codio tab&lt;/strong&gt; - Opens the preview inside a Codio tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default Deployment Target&lt;/strong&gt; - If you&amp;#39;re using the deploy before preview option, this default deployment target specifies which server will be deployed to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Working with Remote Servers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach we take at Codio is to &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; provide the back-end on the Codio infrastructure. So we provide the tools to allow you to integrate as closely and as quickly as possible with your own servers and environments. Whether that be for development or production use. There a lot of good reasons why we don&amp;#39;t provide the back-end:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are now fantastic (and fantastic value-for-money) cloud based development servers available from providers like &lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/"&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; that allow you to configure them exactly as you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have complete freedom of configuration and can create as many development, staging, production environments as you need - all linked to your Codio project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use AWS, Rackspace or absolutely any provider you wish, so you are not restricted in any way at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We stay focused on the IDE side of things, so we can make that experience as perfect as we can, while leaving the back-end to the experts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;The Joy of RSYNC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most remote servers will come with RSYNC enabled. Codio supports an RSYNC deployment target type so that only modified files get deployed. This makes the whole experience really fast. And because Codio is cloud based and your target server is also, deploying is extremely fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Docs and Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see a complete example of the entire process from creating a remote cloud server, right through to deployment, take a look at our &lt;a href="/s/docs/back-end/do-server"&gt;Start to Finish Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Theme: MBO</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/mbo-theme/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/mbo-theme/</id>
    <published>2013-11-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a little goodie for you... we just added an all new theme called MBO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MBO Theme" src="/s/img/blog/mbo-theme-c1f677f7.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change your theme, click the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences... &amp;gt; User&lt;/code&gt; menu item. You will then see the &lt;a href="/s/docs/settings-prefs/codio-prefs/"&gt;preferences editor&lt;/a&gt;. Just add these few lines to the left side of the editor...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little goodie for you... we just added an all new theme called MBO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MBO Theme" src="/s/img/blog/mbo-theme-c1f677f7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change your theme, click the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences... &amp;gt; User&lt;/code&gt; menu item. You will then see the &lt;a href="/s/docs/settings-prefs/codio-prefs/"&gt;preferences editor&lt;/a&gt;. Just add these few lines to the left side of the editor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="ini"&gt;[editor]
theme = mbo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Git Improvements: checkout and revert</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/git-improvements-checkout-and-revert/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/git-improvements-checkout-and-revert/</id>
    <published>2013-11-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of our mission to make working with Git in Codio as natural as working on your desktop, we've added full support for the &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;revert&lt;/code&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Improved &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have always been able to use the &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt; command in Codio to switch...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of our mission to make working with Git in Codio as natural as working on your desktop, we&amp;#39;ve added full support for the &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;revert&lt;/code&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Improved &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have always been able to use the &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt; command in Codio to switch and create branches, but up until now it&amp;#39;s not been possible to use &lt;code&gt;checkout&lt;/code&gt;&amp;#39;s other uses. Now you can...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout [&amp;lt;tree-ish&amp;gt;] [--] &amp;lt;pathspec&amp;gt;...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Support for &lt;code&gt;revert&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revert is almost an complete implementation. Parameters supported:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-m|--mainline parent-number&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-n|--no-commit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;commit&amp;gt;...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty more to come, but post your wanted git commands and options/flags on the &lt;a href="http://forum.codio.com"&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Global Search and Replace</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/search-replace/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/search-replace/</id>
    <published>2013-11-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One big omission from Codio so far has been powerful search and replace functionality across your entire project. We've had search and replace in files, but up until now it's not been possible to search across all files within your project. Well, we...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One big omission from Codio so far has been powerful search and replace functionality across your entire project. We&amp;#39;ve had search and replace in files, but up until now it&amp;#39;s not been possible to search across all files within your project. Well, we&amp;#39;ve corrected this now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="global search dialog" src="/s/img/blog/global-search-b32a1669.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_0"&gt;Globs and pattern matching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as being able to search on simple strings across the entire project, you can use &lt;a href="/s/docs/ide/code-editor/search-replace"&gt;glob pattern matching&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above image shows how you can look for matches of the word &lt;code&gt;step&lt;/code&gt; in all &lt;code&gt;js&lt;/code&gt; files across the whole project. Or, you could look for all files ending in &lt;code&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.coffee&lt;/code&gt; in just the &lt;code&gt;lib&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;lib/*{.html,.coffee}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_1"&gt;Matches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the search operation has completed, you will see all files listed in a Codio tab. Simply double click on the highlighted match to open up that file in a new tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="global search dialog" src="/s/img/blog/search-matches-51e45c9d.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_2"&gt;We&amp;#39;ve open sourced some stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing this, we decided to &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/11/snr/"&gt;open source the back-end&lt;/a&gt; search capabilities. SnR is a Node application and uses &lt;code&gt;ack&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;perl&lt;/code&gt; to provide a powerful way to search within code.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Search and Replace with SnR</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/snr/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/snr/</id>
    <published>2013-11-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Friedel Ziegelmayer</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed, today marked the release of &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/11/search-replace"&gt;global search and replace&lt;/a&gt; in Codio. It's built using the tried and tested tools, &lt;a href="http://beyondgrep.com/"&gt;ack&lt;/a&gt; and perl. While we were building this we realized that it would be great to have a simple command line tool...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed, today marked the release of &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/11/search-replace"&gt;global search and replace&lt;/a&gt; in Codio. It&amp;#39;s built using the tried and tested tools, &lt;a href="http://beyondgrep.com/"&gt;ack&lt;/a&gt; and perl. While we were building this we realized that it would be great to have a simple command line tool to do both search and replace based on these two tools. So today I present the software that came out of that wish: &lt;a href="https://npmjs.org/package/snr"&gt;SnR&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;ve open sourced it and released it as a &lt;a href="https://npmjs.org/package/snr"&gt;Node package&lt;/a&gt;. The source is publicly available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/snr"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As already discussed SnR gives you a simple command line interface to search and replace built on top of &lt;a href="http://beyondgrep.com/"&gt;ack&lt;/a&gt; and perl, and it works like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="bash"&gt;# Inside your project folder
$ snr --replace &amp;quot;console.log&amp;quot; &amp;quot;console.info&amp;quot; &amp;quot;**/*.js&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;How?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started just make sure you have perl and Node (with NPM) installed, and then run &lt;code&gt;npm install -g snr&lt;/code&gt;. That&amp;#39;s it, now you can go and replace all the things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simple usage take a look at these examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="bash"&gt;# Find all occurences of foo inside all python files
$ snr foo &amp;quot;**/*.py&amp;quot;
src/index.js
301-        // catch (e) {
302-        //     //:todo change to correct bar
303:        //     foo(e);
304-        //     //bar(e);
305-        // }
Found 1 match(es) in 1 file(s).
# Replace all occurences of foo with bar inside all python files
$ snr --replace bar foo &amp;quot;**/*.py&amp;quot;
Replaced 1 match(es) in 1 file(s).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and for more advance usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="bash"&gt;$ snr --help
usage: snr [OPTION]... PATTERN [FILES OR DIRECTORIES OR GLOBS]
options:
    -i, --ignore-case       Ignore case distinctions in PATTERN.
    -Q, --literal           Quote all metacharacters; PATTERN is literal.
    --max-result-count=NUM  Stop after NUM results.
    --replace=REPlACE       Replace all matches with REPLACE.
    -h, --help              Print this help and exit.
    -v, --version           Print the current version.
    -C NUM, --context=NUM   Print NUM lines of output context.
    -w, --word-regexp       Force PATTERN to match only whole words.
    --color-lineno=COLOR    Set the color for filenames, matches, and line
                            numbers.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;What&amp;#39;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is even more goodness inside. You can use SnR as a module inside your node app as well, just install it and &lt;code&gt;require(&amp;#39;snr&amp;#39;)&lt;/code&gt; to get started. More info on that can be found on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/snr"&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
