<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codio Blog</title>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Preview of Boxes and Box Parts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/02/boxes/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/02/boxes/</id>
    <published>2014-02-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have been squirreling away on something really big over the last couple of months and wanted to give you a sneak peak. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Codio Boxes&lt;/strong&gt; gives you a dedicated Ubuntu server for each of your Codio projects. Read on for the full details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have been squirreling away on something really big over the last couple of months and wanted to give you a sneak peak. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Codio Boxes&lt;/strong&gt; gives you a dedicated Ubuntu server for each of your Codio projects. Read on for the full details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick your favorite language and watch a video that shows everything you need to know about Boxes and Box Parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node - &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/85953159"&gt;https://vimeo.com/85953159&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby - &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/85998845"&gt;https://vimeo.com/85998845&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP - &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/86028855"&gt;https://vimeo.com/86028855&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Boxes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Box&lt;/strong&gt; is a Ubuntu server that&amp;#39;s created &lt;strong&gt;instantly and invisibly&lt;/strong&gt; to accompany each and every one of your coding projects. You have full access to your Box via the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think you&amp;#39;ll be amazed at how transparent and easy they are to work with. There is no complex setup. Your Box is simply there for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are doing front-end only coding then you don&amp;#39;t even need to be aware of it if that makes you feel better. But if you run things like Grunt for your web sites then having the Box means you can configure and run any build task you like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Box Parts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Box comes with the following preinstalled languages and components&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node&lt;/strong&gt; (with the nvm version manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt; (with rbenv version manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; 2.7 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git, Mercurial and SVN&lt;/strong&gt; SCMs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we also have a big library of so-called &amp;quot;Box Parts&amp;quot; which let you install more databases, languages and components unbelievably quickly. Here&amp;#39;s a selection of the Box Parts we have. If you want more Box Parts, you can just request one here and we will add them for you quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages&lt;/strong&gt;: C,Node, Ruby, Python, PHP (and Composer), Go, Haskell, Java, Lua, Pascla, Rust, Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases&lt;/strong&gt;: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresql, SQLite3, Redis, Memcached&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Servers &amp;amp; Queues&lt;/strong&gt;: Apache2, Nginx, RabbitMQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: ack, ant, apr, cmake, geos, swig, ghc, image_magick, Leiningen, mave, s3cmd, Silver Searcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other&lt;/strong&gt;: PHP Composer, MeteorJS, PhantomJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Shipping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio Boxes is currently in heavy testing. We aim to have it in Production before the end of February 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Easier Uploading</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/02/easier-uploading/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/02/easier-uploading/</id>
    <published>2014-02-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've just made it easier and faster to upload your content to Codio! We've improved uploading in two ways...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Drag and Drop onto the File tree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, you had to open the upload dialog before you could upload anything. Well, we've removed this...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve just made it easier and faster to upload your content to Codio! We&amp;#39;ve improved uploading in two ways...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Drag and Drop onto the File tree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, you had to open the upload dialog before you could upload anything. Well, we&amp;#39;ve removed this requirement completely. While it is still available, you don&amp;#39;t need to open the upload dialog at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, just drag and drop your files directly where you want them. Drag from your desktop and drop into any directory within your project&amp;#39;s file tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Directory Uploading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the latest version of Chrome or Firefox, you can now upload whole directories by simply dragging and dropping them. This allows you to upload more than one file very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="uploading" src="/s/img/blog/uploading-a840dd46.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Server Side Development in Codio</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/server-side-development/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/server-side-development/</id>
    <published>2014-01-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is the best web based IDE for client-side development. However, when it comes to server-side development, things start to get a little tricky. We currently provide no server-side environment where you can run your server code. Over the last few...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is the best web based IDE for client-side development. However, when it comes to server-side development, things start to get a little tricky. We currently provide no server-side environment where you can run your server code. Over the last few months we&amp;#39;ve been working hard to solve this problem, and this week we started opening up Codio Boxes to a select few beta testers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be adding more beta users over the next few weeks. If you want in, drop &lt;a href="mailto:ijobling@codio.com"&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt; an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution has been far from easy, and has made an already complex infrastructure that little bit more complex. But we spent a lot of time thinking and planning the best solution we could possibly provide you. In this post, I want to briefly explain what the new Codio Boxes are and what benefits they will give you when they launch in February 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;New and Shiny&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the following new shiny stuff that will be available to you very soon...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_1"&gt;Docker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of every Codio project is the amazing &lt;a href="https://www.docker.io"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. We wanted every single project to have its own isolated server environment, with terminal access and the ability to do as much as you want without restriction. Docker lets us do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create or open up a project, we spin up a Docker container at the same time. Open up the Codio Terminal and you now have a full-stack server-side development environment in the cloud. We provide a load of languages pre-installed for you, including NodeJS (via &lt;a href="https://github.com/creationix/nvm"&gt;NVM&lt;/a&gt;) and Ruby (via &lt;a href="https://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv"&gt;rbenv&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_2"&gt;Box Parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Box Parts is a simple package manager that we provide, and gives you command line access to quickly install the most popular packages, including MongoDB, PostGreSQL, PHP, Redis and MySQL, &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/boxparts/tree/master/lib/autoparts/packages"&gt;and loads more&lt;/a&gt;. There will be loads more available with more added over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing any of these packages is extremely fast, as we do all the time-consuming compilation steps for you. All you gotta do is install the binaries that we&amp;#39;ve created for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s as easy as &lt;code&gt;parts install mysql&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Box Parts is built with Ruby and is open source. Head on over to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/codio/boxparts"&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; to check it out. This is the place to request missing packages, or - even better - contribute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_3"&gt;Runtime&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every project will also allow you to access your running processes via a public facing domain name. For example, if you want to run a Ruby on Rails server over port 3000, just install Rails and start the Rails server. Then point your browser to &lt;code&gt;YOURPROJECT.USERNAME.codio.com:3000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will allow the port range &lt;code&gt;1024-4096&lt;/code&gt; for your own services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A future blog post will go into further detail about how we are achieving all this, and what technology we are using.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Paid Subscriptions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/subscriptions/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/subscriptions/</id>
    <published>2014-01-14T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce that with immediate effect, you can now purchase a Codio Subscription! This means that for only &lt;strong&gt;$8 per month&lt;/strong&gt;, you can continue to create and keep a &lt;strong&gt;truly unlimited&lt;/strong&gt; number of private and public projects on Codio...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce that with immediate effect, you can now purchase a Codio Subscription! This means that for only &lt;strong&gt;$8 per month&lt;/strong&gt;, you can continue to create and keep a &lt;strong&gt;truly unlimited&lt;/strong&gt; number of private and public projects on Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has a few implications for existing users and we want to clarify what this means for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Public Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no changes here. If you have only public projects in your account then there is no need to take a paid subscription. You can continue to work with as many public projects as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Existing Private Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already created one or more private projects, then we are providing a grace period of 30 days from now, during which time you can keep these projects private without the need to purchase a subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the 30 day grace period, these projects will be disabled. To access such projects, you have two choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch the project from private to public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep them private and purchase a Subscription for $8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you purchase a subscription, all disabled projects will automatically be re-enabled and will be kept private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;New Private Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have not yet purchased a subscription, but you want to create a new private project or switch a public project private, then you will need to purchase a subscription first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Codio Deployment Targets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer several ways to deploy your apps, and one of those involves that we host your static content. This is called the Codio deployment type. This type is now only available to users with a subscription. All other deployment types are still free no matter if you have a Subscription or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;How to Purchase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two place where you can create a Subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/code&gt; menu item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you switch a public project to private (from the &lt;code&gt;Project &amp;gt; Settings&lt;/code&gt; menu item).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see the following screen where you can enter your credit card details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="subscribe" src="/s/img/blog/subscribe-1-d7351dc7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_5"&gt;Group Subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not currently offer this but it is planned in the near future. This will allow a company to manage centralized payments for a group of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_6"&gt;Purchase History &amp;amp; Invoices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be able to find this from the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/code&gt; menu item. You will see the following screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="subscribe" src="/s/img/blog/subscribe-2-f06101a2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_7"&gt;Changing Credit Card Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change your credit card details at any time by going to the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/code&gt; menu item and clicking on the &amp;#39;Card Details&amp;#39; tab.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Happy New Year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/happy-new-year/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2014/01/happy-new-year/</id>
    <published>2014-01-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy new year to you all, and we hope you all had a great Christmas. I'm recovering from too much food and drink and pondering what 2014 will bring. As far as Codio is concerned, it's all guns blazing, and we've got &lt;a href="/s/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/"&gt;BIG plans&lt;/a&gt;. We'll be revealing more...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy new year to you all, and we hope you all had a great Christmas. I&amp;#39;m recovering from too much food and drink and pondering what 2014 will bring. As far as Codio is concerned, it&amp;#39;s all guns blazing, and we&amp;#39;ve got &lt;a href="/s/s/blog/2013/12/git-and-tease-of-what-is-to-come/"&gt;BIG plans&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;ll be revealing more over the coming weeks and months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for now, we&amp;#39;ve got a few goodies that we quietly shipped over the festive period. So think of these as slightly belated Christmas presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;File Templates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest new feature that shipped just before Christmas, was developed by one of our awesome engineers as part of his Friday Hack Day; a weekly day of anything goes hacking on Codio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/s/s/docs/ide/ide-general/templates/"&gt;File Templates&lt;/a&gt; allow you to create a new file based on a selection of code templates, such as a PHP class, or Python script, or even a plain HTML page. When you create a new file, you will have the option of populating that new file with a template of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="templates" src="/s/img/blog/templates-3c4aaaf2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already provide several templates out of the box, but if none of those are what you want, you can also edit these or even create your own templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of several new features and improvements that we have already shipped, and that came out of our weekly Hack Day. Here&amp;#39;s to plenty more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Single click directory opening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another improvement that has come out of us listening to what you want...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you now click a directory name in the file tree, that directory will be expanded without requiring a second click. This makes things more consistent with file opening. Simply put, it means that a single click is all you need to open a file or directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, you can still right-click any item to access the context menu, which includes the ability to rename and delete the item.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tab Cycling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/tab-cycling/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/12/tab-cycling/</id>
    <published>2013-12-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You've been asking and we've been listening. So today we made it easy to quickly switch tabs without having to use your mouse. Just hitting &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+.&lt;/code&gt; will switch your current tab to the next on the right, and &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+,&lt;/code&gt; will switch to tab on the...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ve been asking and we&amp;#39;ve been listening. So today we made it easy to quickly switch tabs without having to use your mouse. Just hitting &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+.&lt;/code&gt; will switch your current tab to the next on the right, and &lt;code&gt;Alt-Shift+,&lt;/code&gt; will switch to tab on the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, if you don&amp;#39;t like those keybindings, open up your &lt;a href="https://codio.com/p/preferences"&gt;preferences&lt;/a&gt; and change the &lt;code&gt;tab_switch_left&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tab_switch_right&lt;/code&gt; item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tab Switching" src="/s/img/blog/tab-switching-944148bf.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
