<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Code and Unload by Codio</title>
  <subtitle>While we code we often have lots of ideas brewing around. Ideas we'd like to unload onto you</subtitle>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>From the Front-line - Issue #1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/07/from-the-frontline-1/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/07/from-the-frontline-1/</id>
    <published>2013-07-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use Twitter - a lot! I also follow and read a lot of blogs and tech news sites. Each day I come across so many useful and interesting articles, libraries, code, apps, frameworks and all manner of coolness. A lot of these are directly or indirectly...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use Twitter - a lot! I also follow and read a lot of blogs and tech news sites. Each day I come across so many useful and interesting articles, libraries, code, apps, frameworks and all manner of coolness. A lot of these are directly or indirectly related to developing for and in the browser - what is sometimes referred to as client-side or front-end development for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, welcome to the very first issue of &amp;quot;From the Front-line&amp;quot;; a regular series of short blog posts which expose the cool side of front end web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.2ality.com/2013/06/basic-javascript.html"&gt;Basic JavaScript: an introduction to the language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - A great starting point for anyone wanting to learn the basics of our best friend; Javascript. Lengthy but worth the read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://davidwalsh.name/add-rules-stylesheets"&gt;Add rules to your Stylesheets with Javascript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Interesting way to style things by adding rules directly to your stylesheets instead of to the DOM, while still using Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a brand new effort to build a CSS animations library that is UI-less and performant. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/h5bp/Effeckt.css"&gt;Effekt.css&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is taking shape nicely and is something that I&amp;#39;m keeping a close eye on. You can see a &lt;a href="http://h5bp.github.io/Effeckt.css/"&gt;work-in-progress demo&lt;/a&gt;. Still plenty to do though ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://topcoat.io"&gt;Topcoat&lt;/a&gt; 0.5.1 is released&lt;/strong&gt; along with &lt;a href="http://topcoat.io/topcoat/"&gt;usage guidelines&lt;/a&gt; which shows off what the Bootstrap competitor has to offer. Looking good, but perhaps a little too Adobe-like for my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand new bug fix &lt;a href="http://blog.jquery.com/2013/07/03/jquery-1-10-2-and-2-0-3-released/"&gt;releases for jQuery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  1.10.2 and 2.0.3 are now available to download.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://emberpress.eviltrout.com/"&gt;EmberPress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a clone of the popular &lt;a href="http://www.atebits.com/letterpress/"&gt;LetterPress&lt;/a&gt; iOS app, but written with the increasingly popular &lt;a href="http://emberjs.com"&gt;EmberJS&lt;/a&gt;. I love the fact that the &lt;a href="http://emberpress.eviltrout.com/docs/emberpress.html"&gt;annotated source code&lt;/a&gt; is available, which uses the brilliant &lt;a href="http://jashkenas.github.io/docco/"&gt;Docco&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to try to publish every week day, so I would appreciate any help. If you find anything that you think would deserve a place in future issues, please &lt;a href="mailto:jmoss@codio.com"&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Removing Apps</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/07/removing-apps/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/07/removing-apps/</id>
    <published>2013-07-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is based upon projects, with a project having any number of files and directories. Codio also has a concept of app's within a project, and that is what you see when creating a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for a long time now, app's have become somewhat...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Codio is based upon projects, with a project having any number of files and directories. Codio also has a concept of app&amp;#39;s within a project, and that is what you see when creating a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for a long time now, app&amp;#39;s have become somewhat of a pain during development and usage of Codio. A project must first have at least one app before it can have a file or directory, and then those files and directories must only be contained within an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is confusing to you, and as Codio has evolved over the last few months, it&amp;#39;s also become unnecessary, and has actually caused us more problems that it solves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will very shortly be removing the concept of app&amp;#39;s within a project, applying the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any existing project that has &lt;strong&gt;only one app&lt;/strong&gt;, will have that app removed, and all it&amp;#39;s files and directories moved into the root of the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any existing project with &lt;strong&gt;more than one app&lt;/strong&gt; will have those app&amp;#39;s changed to plain old directories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;New projects will no longer be created with an app, and instead all files and directories will be located at the project root.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We feel that this change will make things much more flexible for you, and will allow you to structure your projects in any way you please. It will also make things much simpler for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, this change will take place later this week. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codiohq"&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for updates as they happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or queries, please &lt;a href="mailto:help@codio.com"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;, or leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Support added for CoffeeScript, Sass, SCSS etc.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/compiled-files/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/compiled-files/</id>
    <published>2013-06-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're pretty pleased with the latest addition to the Codio IDE. This time, we've added support for the following compiled language types (or whatever the correct collective description is)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're also ready to add...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re pretty pleased with the latest addition to the Codio IDE. This time, we&amp;#39;ve added support for the following compiled language types (or whatever the correct collective description is)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re also ready to add more file types, so tweet &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CodioHQ"&gt;@codioHQ&lt;/a&gt; if you think we should add something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Take a look&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you see below is a real IDE, so play with it to see how we support compiled file types. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press the Preview menu option to run it and see how things are compiled on the fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up the example files (Less and CoffeeScript represented here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want it full size, &lt;a href="https://codio.com/codio/CompilingExample/tree/app/example.coffee" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to see it in its own browser tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width="950" height="600" src="https://codio.com/codio/CompilingExample/tree/app/example.coffee" style="margin:20px 0;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its jolly simple! No build tasks, no separate processes to think about. Just code and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You write your code in CoffeeScript, Less or whatever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You reference anything that results in javascript by appending &lt;code&gt;.js&lt;/code&gt; like this &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;example.coffee.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You reference anything that results in CSS by appending &lt;code&gt;.css&lt;/code&gt;like this &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;style.less.css&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio then compiles the files automatically on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really is jolly simple. Take a quick look at &lt;a href="/s/docs/compiling/one-file/"&gt;User Guide&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;What about production deployment?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, all this only works in development mode. However, in a few weeks we&amp;#39;ll have baked Grunt into Codio, so you will be able to configure build tasks really easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Seeing compiled output&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also really easy to see compiled JS or CSS output for one of your files. The &lt;a href="/s/docs/compiling/one-file/"&gt;User Guide&lt;/a&gt; is the best place to get an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bug reported, fixed and deployed in 50 minutes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/bug-fixed-in-50-minutes/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/bug-fixed-in-50-minutes/</id>
    <published>2013-06-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love how we develop and build software here at Codio. I want to explain quickly just one of the reasons why I love it so much, which also happens to have an immediate effect on you, our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On tuesday morning, our awesome QA team reported a bug...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love how we develop and build software here at Codio. I want to explain quickly just one of the reasons why I love it so much, which also happens to have an immediate effect on you, our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On tuesday morning, our awesome QA team reported a bug related to forking projects. This bug was reported at 9:41am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 9:52am, one of our equally awesome engineers picked up the bug and began work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10:10am is was fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10:26am it was deployed and shipped to the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the time it was known and reported, to the time it was deployed to production was only 50 minutes! That is only possible due to the continuous development and deployment processes that we have in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll try and talk about these processes in a future post. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codiohq"&gt;Follow us&lt;/a&gt; to find out what else we&amp;#39;re up to.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Colour Preview and Picker</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/colour-preview-and-picker/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/colour-preview-and-picker/</id>
    <published>2013-06-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We pushed even more new features this week. Two of the highlights of these are a colour preview and colour picker, accessible from right within the code editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open any CSS file, hover your mouse over a colour value to see a preview of that colour...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We pushed even more new features this week. Two of the highlights of these are a colour preview and colour picker, accessible from right within the code editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open any CSS file, hover your mouse over a colour value to see a preview of that colour. Then click the preview popup to show the colour picker. Then find your perfect colour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It even works with SCSS, SASS and Less files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/s/img/blog/colorpicker-2b225ee2.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy peasy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More thoughts on teaching kids to code</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/coding-kids/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/06/coding-kids/</id>
    <published>2013-06-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we're very busy fashioning lovely new features into the Codio IDE, we are also trying to make some progress with our parallel project of getting kids (around 14 and over) to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Start with a laugh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you want to see how the youth of...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;#39;re very busy fashioning lovely new features into the Codio IDE, we are also trying to make some progress with our parallel project of getting kids (around 14 and over) to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Start with a laugh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you want to see how the youth of today interact with technology, take a quick look at the 15 second video below.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/OyGa9SC-MXQ?autoplay=1" class="fancybox fancybox.iframe" id="video"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;img src="//i3.ytimg.com/vi/OyGa9SC-MXQ/mqdefault.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was taken from this &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/ng7sf2_peFg?autoplay=1"&gt;TedX video&lt;/a&gt; Clare Sutcliffe of &lt;a href="http://codeclub.org.uk/"&gt;CodeClub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;But seriously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows just how natural it is for kids to interact with technology. Apparently the modern term for a kid growing up with today&amp;#39;s tech is a &amp;#39;Digital Native&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, if we do not teach our kids to code, we are missing a major trick and  disadvantaging ourselves and our economies. Teaching them to code should be thought of as a great life skill and one that can reinforce a lot of other school subjects as discussed in this &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/04/coding-art-math/"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the naysayers, yes, some kids will be better than others, but that applies to driving a car or learning mathematics. The fact is, technology is a life skill and coding plays a central part in every application we use on our computers, tablets and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have made a lot of progress in providing a web based platform that is really great for kids above 13 or 14 all the way up to professional developers. By August, it will be ready and free for education, open source and public projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we are trying to do in parallel is devise a way of spreading the word. We are very open to collaborate with anyone, so feel free to email fmay at codio dot com if you have any bright ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More posts on this subject coming.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
