<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Code and Unload by Codio</title>
  <subtitle>While we code we often have lots of ideas brewing around. Ideas we'd like to unload onto you</subtitle>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Codio is Live and Kicking!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/03/codio-is-live-and-kicking/</id>
    <published>2013-03-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce the immediate availability of Codio in public beta. This means you can play with what will become the world's very first IDE that addresses all aspects of the HTML5 development life-cycle right now! We're building...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited to announce the immediate availability of Codio in public beta. This means you can play with what will become the world&amp;#39;s very first IDE that addresses all aspects of the HTML5 development life-cycle right now! We&amp;#39;re building an IDE that any developer will want and enjoy using every single day, because there is currently no such thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don&amp;#39;t take my word for it. &lt;strong&gt;Just click the &amp;quot;Create &amp;amp; Play!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; link at the top of the page to create your first Codio project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Codio IDE" src="/s/img/blog/ide-68ac0fff.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a hard and arduous road, but we&amp;#39;re finally at the start of it. Yes I did say the start, and that&amp;#39;s because we have so much more to come. Building the perfect IDE is no small task you know, but what we&amp;#39;re releasing today is the foundation that will set up that which is to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the press release and subscribe to this blog to stay informed...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Codio today announced its launch in public beta, giving developers of all skill levels access to a powerful, web-based visual IDE for HTML5+CSS+JS development. More than a typical code editor, Codio covers the complete web development cycle, from prototype to deployment. It offers novice developers a barrier free way to learn how to build web applications, but is also targeted very much at professional web developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is a lot of stuff to install, setup and configure before you can write a single line of code. We feel that  there is no good reason for this and even developers, who deal with complexity on a daily basis, don’t like to waste  time. Modern web applications have raised expectations significantly with respect to usability and a web based approach to web development opens up lots of exciting new possibilities. Ultimately, coding should be fun and a happy developer produces happy code!” says CEO Freddy May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evolution of the web has witnessed paradigm shifts in new web technologies. The demand and popularity of web app development has, consequently, secured HTML5, CSS and JavaScript its place among the most popular development  languages. As a large number of modern applications now run in browsers, these technologies have become an integral part of most software development projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By concentrating specifically on HTML5, CSS and JavaScript we can focus on the largest part of the developer ecosystem. This allows us constantly to add significant value that would otherwise not be possible if we were to try to cater for all languages,” says May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the era of the cloud it is logical that web applications should not just run on the web, but also be built on the web. Codio offers developers an efficient, modern, and secure IDE whose code is accessible anywhere online via Codio workspaces and shareable with others in a similar way to Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio makes getting started very simple by allowing developers to use it without even signing up. It offers a comfortable environment not just for code editing but also deployment, collaboration, Git and Mercurial integration, as well as support for derivative languages such as Coffeescript, SCSS, LESS all without the need to install, configure and maintain hardware and software stacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio also brings enhanced collaboration to developers. Traditionally, developers collaborate using web based code repositories such as Github and Bitbucket. Codio supports Source Control Management but also adds real time code editing by multiple developers rather like Google Docs. Text chat, voice chat and video are also planned for later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is being aggressively developed and many new features will be appearing on a continuous deployment basis. Some notable features on the horizon are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-pane code editing&lt;br&gt;
Development, staging, production deployment targets&lt;br&gt;
WYSIWYG GUI editor&lt;br&gt;
Interactive code documentation for teaching&lt;br&gt;
Instant preview&lt;br&gt;
Version control&lt;br&gt;
Node.js support&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio is expected to come out of Public Beta in middle of 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
