<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codio Blog</title>
  <id>https://codio.com/s/blog</id>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog"/>
  <link href="https://codio.com/s/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Codio</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Auto-Complete for Any Language</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/auto-complete-for-any-language/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/auto-complete-for-any-language/</id>
    <published>2013-11-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Up until now, you have been able to use auto-complete for Javascript, HTML and CSS using the keyboard shortcut &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt;. Well now, you can use auto-complete for any language in Codio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio will track common keywords in the file you are editing...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Up until now, you have been able to use auto-complete for Javascript, HTML and CSS using the keyboard shortcut &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt;. Well now, you can use auto-complete for any language in Codio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio will track common keywords in the file you are editing, and provide auto-completion for them all. Just hit &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt; at any time while editing and you will be shown a list of common keywords. And if you type the first few characters of a keyword and hit &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-Space&lt;/code&gt;, you will be shown matches for the characters you just entered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will soon have the ability to automatically show matches without requiring you to hit the keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_0"&gt;Did you know...?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can customise the auto-complete keyboard shortcut, and in fact any other shortcuts that we provide? Open up your preferences (&lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences&lt;/code&gt;) and simply override any of the default shortcuts with whatever you want. &lt;a href="/s/docs/ide/code-editor/kb-shortcuts/"&gt;Read the docs for more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quick Open</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/quick-open/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/quick-open/</id>
    <published>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick open (default is &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt;) also known as fast open, is a great way of opening files without the need to access the file tree. Press &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt; or select &lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt;Open File&lt;/code&gt; from the menu and the quick open dialog will appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quick open" src="/s/img/blog/quick-open-1fbc5512.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick open (default is &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt;) also known as fast open, is a great way of opening files without the need to access the file tree. Press &lt;code&gt;Cmd+O&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt; or select &lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt;Open File&lt;/code&gt; from the menu and the quick open dialog will appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="quick open" src="/s/img/blog/quick-open-1fbc5512.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now start typing the name of a file and as you type, the list will be filtered. You can then select the file you want using the mouse or use the keyboard, pressing &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; on the required file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Selective File Deployment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-specific-files/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-specific-files/</id>
    <published>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although we like to push RSYNC as the fastest way of working with Codio, there are many users who want to work with hosting providers that only provide FTP access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have added a new feature that lets you choose what files or folders...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although we like to push RSYNC as the fastest way of working with Codio, there are many users who want to work with hosting providers that only provide FTP access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have added a new feature that lets you choose what files or folders to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to deploy selectively&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;select any files or folders in the file tree and then right-click and select the Deploy option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;right click in the tab above the file you are editing and do the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="specific files" src="/s/img/blog/deploy-specific-4a409df2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Codio is cloud based and your target FTP server probably is, too, this deployment will be very fast, so developing like this is perfectly possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SSH Public Key Management</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/ssh-public-keys/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/ssh-public-keys/</id>
    <published>2013-11-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our focus is to make all aspects of the development process as smooth and easy as it possibly can be. One small but great example of something that is a real pain in the ass is the business of deploying public keys to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Why are they...&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our focus is to make all aspects of the development process as smooth and easy as it possibly can be. One small but great example of something that is a real pain in the ass is the business of deploying public keys to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Why are they needed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio has two main features that require access to remote servers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH Terminal - you can create and manage any number of remote servers directly from Codio. There&amp;#39;s a &lt;a href="/s/blog/2013/11/ssh/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on this and you can also &lt;a href="/s/docs/ssh"&gt;read the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying via SFTP and RSYNC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most developers prefer to use SSH to access remote servers, as it avoids password entry completely and is more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codio generates public keys that can be found in the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Account&lt;/code&gt; menu. One way of getting your Codio public key on to the remote server is to copy it and then SSH into your remote server and then add it to your &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/authorized_keys&lt;/code&gt; file. However, this is an unnecessary chore. We&amp;#39;ve made it so you can now upload your keys in 2 ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;From your Account dialog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshot below shows how you just need to press the Upload Public Key button and that&amp;#39;s it. You will be asked to enter your access details and that&amp;#39;s it. You can access this dialog via the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Account&lt;/code&gt; menu item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="public key account" src="/s/img/blog/key-account-def388c9.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;From the SSH Connection Manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can SSH into any remote server right from within Codio. In the connections listing, there&amp;#39;s a button you can press that does the same thing as above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="public key account" src="/s/img/blog/key-ssh-6b731019.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Deploy &amp; Preview</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-preview/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/deploy-preview/</id>
    <published>2013-11-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Freddy May</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are constantly looking to streamline your development process when working in Codio, and this time we focused on the ease with which you can deploy and preview code, and in particular back-end code, such as PHP, NodeJS and Python. We've made some...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are constantly looking to streamline your development process when working in Codio, and this time we focused on the ease with which you can deploy and preview code, and in particular back-end code, such as PHP, NodeJS and Python. We&amp;#39;ve made some changes to the way to preview your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Deploying &amp;amp; Previewing Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s say that you make a small modification to a Node or PHP file, and you then want to preview it. All you now need to do is to press the new &lt;code&gt;Preview&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Deploy &amp;amp; Preview&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;Shift-F9&lt;/code&gt;) button in the menu bar and changes get deployed and previewed in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="deploy-preview" src="/s/img/blog/deploy-preview-1-6954e74e.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve added a few extra options to this new button that can be accessed vis the buttons dropdown menu. These options can change the behaviour of the button to help create a workflow suited to your needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy before Preview&lt;/strong&gt; - Deploys your project immediately before previewing. This works perfectly with the Rsync deployment type, as only modified files will get deployed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy in a Codio tab&lt;/strong&gt; - Opens the preview inside a Codio tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default Deployment Target&lt;/strong&gt; - If you&amp;#39;re using the deploy before preview option, this default deployment target specifies which server will be deployed to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Working with Remote Servers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach we take at Codio is to &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; provide the back-end on the Codio infrastructure. So we provide the tools to allow you to integrate as closely and as quickly as possible with your own servers and environments. Whether that be for development or production use. There a lot of good reasons why we don&amp;#39;t provide the back-end:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are now fantastic (and fantastic value-for-money) cloud based development servers available from providers like &lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/"&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; that allow you to configure them exactly as you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have complete freedom of configuration and can create as many development, staging, production environments as you need - all linked to your Codio project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use AWS, Rackspace or absolutely any provider you wish, so you are not restricted in any way at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We stay focused on the IDE side of things, so we can make that experience as perfect as we can, while leaving the back-end to the experts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;The Joy of RSYNC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most remote servers will come with RSYNC enabled. Codio supports an RSYNC deployment target type so that only modified files get deployed. This makes the whole experience really fast. And because Codio is cloud based and your target server is also, deploying is extremely fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Docs and Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see a complete example of the entire process from creating a remote cloud server, right through to deployment, take a look at our &lt;a href="/s/docs/back-end/do-server"&gt;Start to Finish Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Theme: MBO</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/mbo-theme/"/>
    <id>https://codio.com/s/blog/2013/11/mbo-theme/</id>
    <published>2013-11-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Moss</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a little goodie for you... we just added an all new theme called MBO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MBO Theme" src="/s/img/blog/mbo-theme-c1f677f7.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change your theme, click the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences... &amp;gt; User&lt;/code&gt; menu item. You will then see the &lt;a href="/s/docs/settings-prefs/codio-prefs/"&gt;preferences editor&lt;/a&gt;. Just add these few lines to the left side of the editor...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little goodie for you... we just added an all new theme called MBO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MBO Theme" src="/s/img/blog/mbo-theme-c1f677f7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change your theme, click the &lt;code&gt;Codio &amp;gt; Preferences... &amp;gt; User&lt;/code&gt; menu item. You will then see the &lt;a href="/s/docs/settings-prefs/codio-prefs/"&gt;preferences editor&lt;/a&gt;. Just add these few lines to the left side of the editor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="ini"&gt;[editor]
theme = mbo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
